<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.r4pumm"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0128114-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.r4pumm</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-06
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Lasthenia californica DC. ex Lindl.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
1 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
1 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
1 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
1 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
1 records from Texas Tech University, E. L. Reed Herbarium
1 records from Muestreos y recolectas de flora endémica y casi-endémica de matorral costero y chaparral de la zona mediterránea Baja California, México
1 records from Michigan State University Herbarium Vascular Plants
1 records from Botany (UPS)
1 records from SFSU - Vascular Plants of the Harry D. Thiers Herbarium at San Francisco State University
1 records from Agnes Marion Ayre Herbarium (NFLD)
1 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
1 records from University of Jena, Herbarium Haussknecht - Herbarium JE
1 records from IAC - Herbário do Instituto Agronômico de Campinas
1 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
1 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Palynology Collection
1 records from Staten Island Museum
1 records from Royal BC Museum - Herbarium (V)
1 records from Museu Paraense Emilio Goeldi Herbarium
1 records from Plantas de La Frontera (ecorregión 12.1.1.1), e inventario florístico del Rancho El Aribabi, municipio de Imuris, Sonora
1 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
1 records from CONN
1 records from Estonian University of Life Sciences Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Vascular Plant Herbarium
1 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
1 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
2 records from Vascular Plant Collection - University of Washington Herbarium (WTU)
2 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
2 records from BLM - National Landscape Monitoring Framework - Plants
2 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
2 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
2 records from CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino
2 records from Bell Museum plants
2 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
2 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
2 records from K herbarium - Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from Herbarium Horti Botanici Pisani (PI), Sistema Museale di Ateneo, Università di Pisa
2 records from University of Alberta Vascular Plant Herbarium (ALTA-VP)
2 records from Flora de las playas y dunas costeras de México
2 records from Geneva Herbarium – De Candolle&apos;s Prodromus (G-DC)
3 records from Kathryn Kalmbach Herbarium
3 records from Botany Division, Yale Peabody Museum
3 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
3 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
3 records from LSU Shirley C. Tucker Herbarium at Louisiana State University - Vascular Plants
3 records from INRAE Villa Thuret
3 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
3 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
4 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
4 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
4 records from Clemson University Herbarium
4 records from Pl@ntNet automatically identified occurrences
4 records from El banco de datos del Herbario HCIB en línea (Fase I): Implementación del Sistema Biótica
4 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
4 records from H.A. Stephens Herbarium
6 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
6 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
6 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
7 records from MCCC - Mendocino College Coast Center Herbarium
8 records from Université Lyon 1
8 records from University of Lethbridge Herbarium (LEA)
9 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
9 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
10 records from Catálogo electrónico de especímenes depositados en el Herbario de la Universidad de Texas en Austin, Fase IV (Ejemplaresimagenes)
11 records from Plant Resources Center
12 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
12 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
12 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
13 records from Rutgers University, Chrysler Herbarium
14 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
16 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
17 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
21 records from Vascular Plant Collection
23 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
23 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
23 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
24 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
24 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
25 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
26 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
30 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
31 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
33 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
34 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
35 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
40 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
40 records from Puntos de presencia en Baja California (Botany)
42 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
42 records from PUA - Pacific Union College Hebarium
47 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
48 records from INSDC Sequences
50 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
60 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
67 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
72 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
75 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
79 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
79 records from NatureServe Network Species Occurrence Data
80 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
161 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
181 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
263 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
331 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
347 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
886 records from CAS Botany (BOT)</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-06T23:18:39Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.r4pumm">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.r4pumm</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0128114-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
