<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.z3334v"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130578-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.z3334v</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Amsinckia menziesii (Lehm.) A.Nelson &amp; J.F.Macbr.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
1 records from Herbarium Willing at Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
1 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
1 records from SER Site-based Surveys
1 records from Herbarium of Umeå University (UME)
1 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
1 records from Löydös Open Finnish Observation Database
1 records from MISS_DC_01MAR2006
1 records from Species recordings from the Danish National portal Arter.dk
1 records from Botany Division, Yale Peabody Museum
1 records from Dr Mary Gillham Archive Project
1 records from Vascular Herbarium, NMBU
1 records from Pittsburg State University, Theodore M. Sperry Herbarium
1 records from University of Manitoba Herbarium (WIN) - Vascular Plant Collection
1 records from Hatikka.fi observations
1 records from Seed collection – dead seeds for evaluation and observation purposes
1 records from Merseyside BioBank (verified)
1 records from Herbier du Québec (QUE) - Collection de plantes vasculaires
1 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
1 records from PlutoF platform reference-based occurrences
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
1 records from Sheffield and Rotherham Wildlife Trust - Records
1 records from Kenai National Wildlife Refuge, Alaska (KNWR) Plant specimens (Arctos)
1 records from Royal Ontario Museum Green Plant Herbarium (TRT)
1 records from North Merseyside Local Species Data (DEFRA Grant 23169)
1 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
1 records from Merseyside BioBank (unverified)
1 records from Brock University Herbarium (BU)
1 records from Rutgers University, Chrysler Herbarium
1 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
1 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
1 records from Depuración de la colección y base de datos del Herbario CICY. Fase IV
1 records from El banco de datos del Herbario HCIB en línea (Fase I): Implementación del Sistema Biótica
1 records from NEON Biorepository Terrestrial Plant Collection (Herbarium Vouchers)
1 records from Tallinn Botanic Garden
1 records from Hertfordshire Flora Survey Records 1987-2005
1 records from CONN
1 records from H.A. Stephens Herbarium
1 records from University of Lethbridge Herbarium (LEA)
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - Alaska, United States
1 records from Observations.be - Non-native species occurrences in Wallonia, Belgium
1 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
2 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
2 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
2 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum Görlitz (GLM)
2 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
2 records from Bell Museum plants
2 records from MHA Herbarium: collections of vascular plants
2 records from Michigan State University Herbarium Vascular Plants
2 records from Cumbria Non Native Invasive Species
2 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
2 records from Agnes Marion Ayre Herbarium (NFLD)
2 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
2 records from Montana State University Billings
2 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
2 records from CANB AVH data
2 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium: Herbarium Generale
2 records from Plant collection Natuurmuseum Brabant, Tilburg
2 records from Inventario florístico de la familia Boraginaceae en México. Fase II
2 records from Victorian Biodiversity Atlas
2 records from Local floras of Russia: a compilative dataset
2 records from All taxa records for Leicestershire and Rutland
2 records from Estonian University of Life Sciences Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Vascular Plant Herbarium
2 records from RHS monitoring of native and naturalised plants and animals at its gardens and surrounding areas
3 records from Botanical Collections of the Åbo Akademi (TUR-A)
3 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
3 records from Plant Resources Center
3 records from Nijmegen Natural History Museum (NL) - Herbarium
3 records from Bruce Bennett Herbarium (BABY)
3 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
3 records from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium
3 records from RECORD Vascular Plant Data
3 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
4 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
4 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
4 records from FBIP: Great Escarpment Biodiversity Research Programme data mobilisation
4 records from GRBGT: Southern Cape Herbarium Specimen Collections (1882-2008)
4 records from BRERC species records from all years at full resolution excluding Notable Species within the last 10 years
5 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
5 records from Natural History Museum Rotterdam - Specimens
5 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
5 records from Vascular plant herbarium TRH, NTNU University Museum
5 records from NBIS Records to December 2016
5 records from Weber State University Herbarium
5 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
5 records from Université Lyon 1
5 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
6 records from Kathryn Kalmbach Herbarium
6 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
6 records from INSDC Sequences
6 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
7 records from TUR Vascular plant collections of the Turku University, Herbarium generale
7 records from Herbier Louis-Marie (QFA) - Collection de plantes vasculaires
7 records from Oskarshamn herbarium (OHN)
8 records from CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino
8 records from Botany (UPS)
8 records from Welsh BSBI data (ex-VPDB dataset) at hectad resolution
8 records from MEL AVH data
8 records from PUA - Pacific Union College Hebarium
8 records from Pl@ntNet observations
9 records from Rotherham Biological Records Centre - Non-sensitive Records from all taxonomic groups
10 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
10 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
10 records from PRECIS
11 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
11 records from Kastikka Floristic Archives (Kastikka Ark)
11 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Herbarium
11 records from Shropshire Ecological Data Network database
12 records from Norwegian Species Observation Service
12 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
12 records from Flora of Worcestershire
12 records from Phytochorologie des départements français
12 records from Occurrence Data of Vascular Plants collected or compiled for the Flora of Bavaria
12 records from naturgucker
12 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
14 records from Pl@ntNet automatically identified occurrences
14 records from The Danish Environmental Portal, species and habitats-database &quot;Danmarks Miljøportals Naturdatabase&quot;
14 records from Yorkshire Wildlife Trust - Non-sensitive records from all taxonomic groups
15 records from INPN - Données flore des CBN agrégées par la FCBN
16 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
16 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
17 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
17 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
19 records from LERN Records
19 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
20 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
20 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
22 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
22 records from FSC - Fresno State Herbarium
23 records from BODATSA: Botanical Collections
25 records from FLORIVON
25 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
26 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
26 records from National Trust Species Records
27 records from Flora von Deutschland (Phanerogamen)
28 records from Observations du Conservatoire botanique national du Bassin parisien.
29 records from UAM Herbarium (ALA), Vascular Plant Collection (Arctos)
30 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
33 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
34 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
34 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
36 records from Puntos de presencia en Baja California (Botany)
38 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
42 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
46 records from Dutch Vegetation Database
47 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
55 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
57 records from Royal BC Museum - Herbarium (V)
58 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
58 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
62 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
72 records from Florabank1 - A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in the northern part of Belgium (Flanders and the Brussels Capital region)
78 records from Vascular plant records verified via iRecord
79 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
86 records from Vascular Plant Collection - University of Washington Herbarium (WTU)
93 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
93 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
97 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
100 records from Scottish SNH-funded BSBI records
103 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
125 records from Vascular Plant Collection
146 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
156 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
157 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
208 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
218 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
240 records from Artportalen (Swedish Species Observation System)
247 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
258 records from Waarnemingen.be - Non-native plant occurrences in Flanders and the Brussels Capital Region, Belgium
395 records from Other BSBI Scottish data up to 2015
464 records from Suffolk Biodiversity Information Service (SBIS) Dataset
484 records from Atlas Flora Danica
871 records from BSBI data from several English counties, up to 2015
1062 records from Observation.org, Nature data from around the World</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T03:27:51Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.z3334v">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.z3334v</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130578-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
