<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.a3mn8j"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130757-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.a3mn8j</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Brassica tournefortii Gouan&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Dataflos
1 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
1 records from Instituto Pirenaico de Ecología-CSIC: Herbarium JACA
1 records from Herbário João de Carvalho e Vasconcellos, I.S.A./U.L.
1 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Olivier ESCUDER
1 records from Herbario EMMA. Herbario de la Escuela Técnica Superior de Ingenieros de Montes. UPM
1 records from RL Minckley Insect and Plant Collection
1 records from MEXU/Plantas Vasculares
1 records from inatura - Erlebnis Naturschau Dornbirn
1 records from Plant specimens in the Museum of Nature and Human Activities, Hyogo Prefecture, Japan
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad Pública de Navarra, Pamplona: UPNA-H
1 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO-Briof
1 records from Dr Mary Gillham Archive Project
1 records from Bush Heritage - Carnarvon Station Reserve
1 records from VIT Herbarium - Vascular Plants (The Natural History Museum of Alava)
1 records from FloraCAT: Banco de datos de los cormófitos de Cataluña
1 records from Herbarium specimens, Harmas J.H. Fabre (FABR - Sérignan-du-Comtat) of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
1 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
1 records from LERN Records
1 records from Chapter 7: Linnaean Plant Names and their Types (part S)
1 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
1 records from Catalogue of type specimens of vascular plants deposited in the Herbarium of the University of Granada (Spain)
1 records from Seed collection – dead seeds for evaluation and observation purposes
1 records from Herbario del Jardín Botánico-Histórico La Concepción: HBC
1 records from Botany (UPS)
1 records from HAS - Herbário Alarich Rudolf Holger Schultz
1 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2018
1 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
1 records from Institut Menorquí d&apos;Estudis. Colección Histórica de Rodríguez Femenías, Herbarium Generale Minoricae: HGM-Femenias
1 records from Vascular plant herbarium, UiT Tromsø Museum
1 records from Universidad de Navarra, Herbarium: PAMP-Vascular Plants
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - United States (Contiguous) V2.0
1 records from Flora von Deutschland (Phanerogamen)
1 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - SPNI
1 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
1 records from Herbarium GB, University of Gothenburg
1 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
1 records from Database of Vascular Plants of Himalaya
1 records from Olga Lakela Herbarium, University of Minnesota Duluth
1 records from Clemson University Herbarium
1 records from University of Alberta Vascular Plant Herbarium (ALTA-VP)
1 records from CNS AVH data
1 records from UKSBA Cyprus Plant Records 2018
1 records from Muséum d’histoire naturelle de Grenoble
1 records from Vascular plant herbarium (KMN) UiA
1 records from Bioversity Collecting Mission Database
1 records from Catálogo electrónico de especímenes depositados en el Herbario de la Universidad de Texas en Austin, Fase IV (Ejemplaresimagenes)
1 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
1 records from Carnarvon Basin wetland survey
1 records from Manchester Museum, University of Manchester, Botany Collection
1 records from Natural History Museum Maastricht (NL) - Herbarium
1 records from Wikiplantbase #Toscana
1 records from Masaryk University - Herbarium BRNU
1 records from PUA - Pacific Union College Hebarium
1 records from Actualización de la base de datos del Herbario de la Universidad de Sonora (USON)
1 records from Flora-On: occurrence data of the flora of mainland Portugal
2 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO
2 records from Herbarium of Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Extremadura (Spain)
2 records from BLM - National Landscape Monitoring Framework - Plants
2 records from CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino
2 records from UKSBA Cyprus - Habitat Samples, 2019
2 records from Texas Tech University, E. L. Reed Herbarium
2 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Herbarium Tubingense
2 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
2 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
2 records from NatureShare
2 records from Carnet en Ligne
2 records from Vascular plant herbarium TRH, NTNU University Museum
2 records from WildNet - Queensland Wildlife Data
2 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
2 records from CIRAD
2 records from B herbarium - Botanischer Garten und Botanisches Museum Berlin-Dahlem Herbarium - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from Florabank1 - A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in the northern part of Belgium (Flanders and the Brussels Capital region)
2 records from El banco de datos del Herbario HCIB en línea (Fase I): Implementación del Sistema Biótica
2 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
2 records from FSC - Fresno State Herbarium
2 records from CSLA - Cal State LA Herbarium
2 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
2 records from MBM herbarium - Museu Botânico Municipal \ Curitiba - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
2 records from Geneva Herbarium – De Candolle&apos;s Prodromus (G-DC)
2 records from naturgucker
2 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
3 records from Aranzadi Zientzi Elkartea
3 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
3 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
3 records from NE AVH data
3 records from Base de datos de plantas vasculares del País Vasco: ARAN-EH
3 records from Banksia Woodlands Restoration Project Survey
3 records from BODATSA: Botanical Collections
3 records from Charles University Prague - Herbarium PRC
3 records from Plantas de La Frontera (ecorregión 12.1.1.1), e inventario florístico del Rancho El Aribabi, municipio de Imuris, Sonora
3 records from Flora de las playas y dunas costeras de México
3 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
3 records from Oskarshamn herbarium (OHN)
4 records from Observation.org, Nature data from around the World
4 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
4 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Olivier ESCUDER
4 records from Flora of Worcestershire
4 records from Earth Guardians Weekly Feed
4 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2017
4 records from Phytochorologie des départements français
4 records from MACF - MacFadden Herbarium, California State University Fullerton
4 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
4 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
4 records from Waarnemingen.be - Non-native plant occurrences in Flanders and the Brussels Capital Region, Belgium
5 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
5 records from Espèces Végétales Menacées de France métropolitaine
5 records from Plant Resources Center
5 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Ciencias Biológicas de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MACB)
5 records from University of Jena, Herbarium Haussknecht - Herbarium JE
5 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
5 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
5 records from Swan Coastal Plain Survey
5 records from Wikiplantbase Sicilia
5 records from Plants of Scotia Sanctuary
6 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Almería
6 records from ALA species sightings and OzAtlas
6 records from Precis Plant Data
6 records from Banded Iron Formation and Greenstone survey data
6 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
6 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
6 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
7 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
7 records from Vascular Plant Specimen database of Kanagawa Prefectural Museum of Natural History
7 records from INSDC Sequences
7 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
7 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
7 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, UiB
7 records from Weed and native flora data for the Swan Coastal Plain
7 records from Quaid-i-Azam University Herbarium
7 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
8 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB
9 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares de la Universidad de Salamanca: SALA
9 records from Wikiplantbase #Sardegna
9 records from Localización de táxones botánicos de interés para la identificación de hábitats de la REDIAM (Secretaría General de Medio Ambiente, Agua y Cambio Climático)
9 records from Malezas introducidas en México
9 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
9 records from Cartografía de vegetación a escala de detalle 1:10.000 de la masa forestal de Andalucía
10 records from MGC Herbarium of University of Malaga (Spain): MGC-Cormof dataset
10 records from Herbario de Universidad de Murcia: MUB
10 records from Tasmanian Natural Values Atlas
11 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB, CSIC-Ajuntament de Barcelona), BC-Plantae
11 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
12 records from CeDoc de Biodiversitat Vegetal: BCN-Cormophyta
12 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla
12 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
12 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
14 records from Scottish SNH-funded BSBI records
15 records from Conservation Atlas Surveys
15 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
15 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
16 records from Jardín Botánico de Córdoba: Herbarium COA
16 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
16 records from HO AVH data
17 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
18 records from Carnarvon Basin upland survey
18 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
20 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium: Herbarium Generale
20 records from Greenstone Ranges Survey
21 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
22 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
22 records from PRECIS
22 records from BSBI data from several English counties, up to 2015
23 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
23 records from Other BSBI Scottish data up to 2015
25 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
25 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario de la Universidad de Granada.
25 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
26 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL)
27 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
27 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
28 records from Sistema de Información de la vegetación Ibérica y Macaronésica
29 records from Herbario ABH (Universidad de Alicante)
29 records from Universidad Politécnica de Madrid, Dpto. Biología Vegetal, Banco de Germoplasma
29 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
29 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
34 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
34 records from Observations floristiques - plateforme SINP régionale SILENE   PACA
38 records from Allan Herbarium (CHR)
39 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - INPA database
40 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
40 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - A. Danin&apos;s point database
44 records from NHMO DNA Bank Vascular plants collection
46 records from Puntos de presencia en Baja California (Botany)
46 records from INRAE Villa Thuret
47 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
47 records from Shark Bay Survey
50 records from BRI AVH data
56 records from DNA AVH data
57 records from INPN - Données flore des CBN agrégées par la FCBN
58 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
59 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Anthos. Sistema de Información de las Plantas de España
60 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
61 records from Banco de Datos de la Biodiversidad de la Comunitat Valenciana
65 records from Université Lyon 1
66 records from MEL AVH data
70 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - Israeli Gene Bank
77 records from NSW AVH data
82 records from Salinity Action Plan Flora Survey
84 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
90 records from United Herbaria of the University and ETH Zurich
92 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
95 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - A. Danin&apos;s grid database
101 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
111 records from CANB AVH data
112 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
112 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
163 records from PERTH AVH data
166 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
173 records from Israel Nature and Parks Authority
212 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
219 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
232 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
246 records from Flora Atlas N.T.
255 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
534 records from Australasian Virtual Herbarium (AVH) data from the State Herbarium of South Australia (AD)
894 records from NSW BioNet Atlas
1807 records from BLM - National Invasive Species Information Management System - Plants
1892 records from A global database for the distributions of crop wild relatives
2067 records from Victorian Biodiversity Atlas
7026 records from SA Flora (BDBSA)</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T04:20:14Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.a3mn8j">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.a3mn8j</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130757-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
