<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.nj42ht"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130359-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.nj42ht</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Clarkia purpurea (Curtis) A.Nelson &amp; J.F.Macbr.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla, SEV-Historico
1 records from Botanical Museum, Copenhagen. Database of type specimens
1 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
1 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
1 records from Colorado State University Herbarium
1 records from Herbarium of University of Coimbra (COI )
1 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
1 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
1 records from Seed collection – dead seeds for evaluation and observation purposes
1 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
1 records from Michigan State University Herbarium Vascular Plants
1 records from Botany (UPS)
1 records from Plant Resources Center
1 records from CEN - Herbário da Embrapa Recursos Genéticos e Biotecnologia
1 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
1 records from South Dakota State University, C. A. Taylor Herbarium
1 records from University of Graz, Institute of Plant Sciences - Herbarium GZU
1 records from PACA-AGP - Herbarium Anchieta
1 records from Olga Lakela Herbarium, University of Minnesota Duluth
1 records from Sistematización de la colección entomológica y actualización de la colección del herbario CHIP del Instituto de Historia Natural y Ecología (IHNE), Chiapas (Plantas)
1 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Palynology Collection
1 records from Catálogo electrónico de especímenes depositados en el Herbario de la Universidad de Texas en Austin, Fase IV (Ejemplaresimagenes)
1 records from El banco de datos del Herbario HCIB en línea (Fase I): Implementación del Sistema Biótica
1 records from 500,000 plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1950 to 1999
1 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
1 records from Manchester Museum, University of Manchester, Botany Collection
1 records from Natural History Museum Maastricht (NL) - Herbarium
1 records from LSU Shirley C. Tucker Herbarium at Louisiana State University - Vascular Plants
1 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany) - Historical Photographs of Type Specimens from Berlin (B)
1 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
1 records from The Fungal Collection at the Senckenberg Museum für Naturkunde Görlitz
1 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
1 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
2 records from Bell Museum plants
2 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
2 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
2 records from Clemson University Herbarium
2 records from IAC - Herbário do Instituto Agronômico de Campinas
2 records from Staten Island Museum
2 records from UCBG TAPIR Provider
2 records from CONN
2 records from Sammlung altes Gartenherbar Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
3 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
3 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
3 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
3 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
3 records from INSDC Sequences
3 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
3 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
4 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
4 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
4 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
4 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
4 records from NatureServe Network Species Occurrence Data
6 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
6 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
6 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
6 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
6 records from Royal BC Museum - Herbarium (V)
6 records from University of Lethbridge Herbarium (LEA)
7 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
7 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
7 records from Florística de la reserva de la biósfera de Mapimí
8 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
9 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
10 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
10 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
11 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
11 records from Puntos de presencia en Baja California (Botany)
11 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
12 records from CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino
14 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
17 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
17 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
19 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
20 records from Université Lyon 1
23 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
27 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
30 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
33 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
33 records from FSC - Fresno State Herbarium
34 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
40 records from PUA - Pacific Union College Hebarium
40 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
48 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
50 records from Vascular Plant Collection - University of Washington Herbarium (WTU)
54 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
54 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
65 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
76 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
91 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
110 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
114 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
143 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
146 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
185 records from Vascular Plant Collection
245 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
248 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
250 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
273 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
291 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
320 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
685 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
791 records from CAS Botany (BOT)</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T02:19:48Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.nj42ht">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.nj42ht</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130359-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
