<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.myffab"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130501-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.myffab</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Clarkia bottae (Spach) H. &amp; Lewis&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
1 records from Western Carolina University Herbarium
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
1 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
1 records from INSDC Sequences
1 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
1 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
1 records from CONN
1 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
1 records from The Fungal Collection at the Senckenberg Museum für Naturkunde Görlitz
2 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
2 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
2 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
2 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
2 records from Université Lyon 1
2 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
3 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
3 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
3 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
4 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
4 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
5 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
6 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
6 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
6 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
6 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
8 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
10 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
14 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
18 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
22 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
27 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
31 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
36 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
37 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
37 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
38 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
39 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
55 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
100 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
117 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
203 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T03:04:52Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.myffab">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.myffab</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130501-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
