<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.tj9zn7"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130533-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.tj9zn7</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Medicago polymorpha L.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Catálogos florísticos de México por entidad federativa e información etnobotánica de la Colección del Herbario Nacional Biól. Luciano Vela Gálvez (INIF)
1 records from Florística de áreas protegidas en el estado de Durango
1 records from Catálogo y base de datos preliminar de la flora de Sinaloa
1 records from Estudio etnobotánico de las malezas útiles presentes en diferentes agroecosistemas en el municipio de Santa María Tecomavaca, Valle de Tehuacán-Cuicatlán, México
1 records from Flora vascular de Torca, Localidad de Usaquén (Bogotá - Colombia)
1 records from Leiner-Herbar Konstanz
1 records from Mountain Invasion Research Network (MIREN) survey
1 records from Plant Specimens of Lake Biwa Museum
1 records from Spermatophyta specimens of Iwate Prefectural Museum
1 records from Plant specimens of Taga Town Museum, Shiga Pref., Japan
1 records from MEXU/Colección Histórica
1 records from HCF herbarium - Universidade Tecnológica Federal do Paraná - Campus Campo Mourão - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Clémence Lortet herbarium
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - Hawaii, United States
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente 2013
1 records from Patrick Roper’s Notebooks
1 records from Floristic records from survey studies of the Bayerisches Landesamt für Umwelt
1 records from Collection botanique É. Juttin (BOUM)
1 records from Polish gene bank – passport data of plants accessions which are important in human life
1 records from Naturnahes Tal in Siena
1 records from Jardín Botánico Atlántico, Gijón/Xixón: Herbarium JBAG
1 records from Botany Division, Yale Peabody Museum
1 records from MEXU/Flora de Oaxaca
1 records from Database of Native Plants in Taiwan
1 records from Bush Heritage - Carnarvon Station Reserve
1 records from CEN herbarium -  Embrapa Recursos Genéticos e Biotecnologia - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Natural History Museum Rotterdam - Specimens
1 records from Spermatophytes collection of Okinawa Prefectural Museum &amp; Art Museum
1 records from Western Carolina University Herbarium
1 records from Pittsburg State University, Theodore M. Sperry Herbarium
1 records from Jeu de données convention Eurovia-SPN-2012-2016
1 records from Natura 2000 Vallée de la Seille
1 records from Convention Fédération française de golf - MNHN 2016-2019.
1 records from HVAT - Herbário do Vale do Taquari
1 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (LBG) in China, Lushan Botanical Garden, Jiangxi and Chinese Academy of Sciences
1 records from FURB - Herbário Dr. Roberto Miguel Klein
1 records from CRI - Herbário Pe. Dr. Raulino Reitz
1 records from Inventaire de la flore des Deux-Sèvres 2013
1 records from Monitoring of non-crop plants in organic fields of Mauritius
1 records from CEPEC - Herbário do Centro de Pesquisas do Cacau
1 records from Plant specimens of Bihoro Museum
1 records from Colección del Herbario PSO de la Universidad de Nariño
1 records from ERBG AVH data
1 records from Sammmlung Ule Brasilien Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
1 records from Herbier du Québec (QUE) - Collection de plantes vasculaires
1 records from Données naturalistes de Jeanne VALLET
1 records from Leicestershire and Rutland Environmental Records Centre records 2015-2019
1 records from JPB - Herbário Lauro Pires Xavier
1 records from PlutoF platform reference-based occurrences
1 records from Base de datos computarizada del herbario CIB, Instituto de Investigaciones Biológicas, Universidad Veracruzana
1 records from Chapter 7: Linnaean Plant Names and their Types (part M)
1 records from Carnet B Lorraine
1 records from PEUFR - Herbário Professor Vasconcelos Sobrinho
1 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Yves BAS
1 records from Plant specimens of Tama City Cultural Foundation
1 records from Proyecto interno ejecutado por la CONABIO: Sistema de información sobre Bosque Mesófilo de Montaña de México para apoyo en programas de restauración (Fase 1)
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - United States (Contiguous) V2.0
1 records from HCF - Herbário da Universidade Tecnológica Federal do Paraná Campus Campo Mourão
1 records from Inventario florístico de la Reserva de la Biosfera Mariposa Monarca, México
1 records from Plant Observation Records of Japan
1 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
1 records from HPL - Herbário do Jardim Botânico Plantarum
1 records from Digitization of plant specimens from Rhoen and Vogelsberg (FULD)
1 records from CEN - Herbário da Embrapa Recursos Genéticos e Biotecnologia
1 records from Atlas of Life in the Coastal Wilderness
1 records from Museo Argentino de Ciencias Naturales &quot;Bernardino Rivadavia&quot; (MACN). Actuopalynology National Collection (BAPa)
1 records from Conventions d’étude sur la biodiversité française – Partenariats du Service du patrimoine naturel
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Jardins botaniques and Conservatoire Botanique of Nancy (NCY)
1 records from African Plants - a photo guide
1 records from IPS Golfs
1 records from FURB herbarium - Universidade Regional de Blumenau - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from LTB AVH data
1 records from CRI Herbarium - Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense - Herbário Virtual Reflora
1 records from RNF - Données du Syndicat de Gestion des Gorges de l&apos;Ardêche
1 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2016
1 records from Arkansas Natural Heritage Commission Herbarium
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 30
1 records from SPF herbarium - Universidade de são Paulo - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Species biodiversity transnational geo-database - IMPRECO Project
1 records from Plant specimens of Takatsuki Nature Museum (Aquapia Akutagawa)
1 records from HRCB - Herbário Rioclarense
1 records from Marie-Victorin Herbarium (MT) - Plantes vasculaires
1 records from n_niek_2021
1 records from UNSW AVH data
1 records from Dorset SSSI Species Records 1952 - 2004 (Natural England)
1 records from HSS-carpoteca (HSS-C) Finca La Orden-Valdesequera (CICYTEX). Junta de Extremadura
1 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in Sierra del Mendaur (Navarra, Spain). Undergraduate thesis, C. García-Zamora
1 records from Données faune, flore et fonge du Conservatoire des espaces naturels de Picardie
1 records from Plant specimens of Toyota City Nature Sanctuary
1 records from Swan Coastal Plain Survey
1 records from SPSF - Herbário Dom Bento José Pickel
1 records from Computarización de las colectas del estado de Morelos depositadas en el Herbario HUMO de la Universidad Autónoma del Estado de Morelos
1 records from CHAS Botany Collection (Arctos)
1 records from Collection d&apos;animaux marins et plantes du Museum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle de Nice
1 records from niek_2022
1 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in Pamplona Basin (Navarra, Spain). Undergraduate thesis, D. Vicente
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de la Vienne 2015
1 records from Herbario Pontificia Universidad Javeriana
1 records from IICT Herbário LISC
1 records from Herbario Universidad de Antioquia (HUA)
1 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (CDBI) in China, Chengdu Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences
1 records from Shropshire Ecological Data Network database
1 records from Inventaire de la flore du Pays Bassin d&apos;Arcachon - Val de l&apos;Eyre 2010-2013
1 records from RECORD Vascular Plant Data
1 records from FBIP: DNA barcode reference library for plants from Addo Elephant National Park for herbivore diet  studies
1 records from BioFokus
1 records from Estudio florístico, ecológico y etnobotánico, en el área natural protegida &quot;Tenancingo-Malinalco-Zumpahuacan&quot;, Estado de México
1 records from Museu Paraense Emilio Goeldi Herbarium
1 records from El banco de datos del Herbario HCIB en línea (Fase I): Implementación del Sistema Biótica
1 records from Flora de las playas y dunas costeras de México
1 records from Herbario Gaspar Xuarez (BAA) - Facultad de Agronomía - Universidad de Buenos Aires
1 records from Shark Bay Survey
1 records from Plant specimens of Otaru City Museum
1 records from Collection botanique Jaubert et Saul (BOUM)
1 records from Herbario SQF
1 records from Herbarium Universitatis Daugavpiliensis
1 records from Geneva Herbarium – Burnat Herbarium (G-BU)
1 records from HDCF herbarium - Universidade Federal de Santa Maria - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Steiermärkisches Landesmuseum Joanneum - Herbarium GJO
1 records from Colección Botánica-Herbario. Museo de Ciencias Naturales y Antropológicas “Juan Cornelio Moyano” (Mendoza, Argentina)
1 records from ALCB - Herbário Alexandre Leal Costa
1 records from Indicateur Petits Sites SUEZ
1 records from Vascular plants of the Valleys of Hell, Danniye-Akkar, Lebanon, 2019
1 records from UAM Herbarium (ALA), Vascular Plant Collection (Arctos)
1 records from HPBR - Herbário Padre Balduino Rambo
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - Alaska, United States
1 records from Fungus Collections at Staatliches Museum für Naturkunde Karlsruhe (Herbarium KR)
1 records from Données de la base Ecosphère
1 records from FBIP:RU:Floristic Survey
1 records from The Danish Environmental Portal, species and habitats-database &quot;Danmarks Miljøportals Naturdatabase&quot;
1 records from OAC-BIO Herbarium
1 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2014
1 records from Inventaire de la flore du PNRLG 2017 (Landes)
1 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2017
1 records from Flora Atlas N.T.
1 records from UEC - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Campinas
1 records from Vascular plant specimens of Akita Prefectural Museum
1 records from Vascular plants database of Atsugi City Museum
1 records from Angiospermatatophytina Collection of Saitama Museum of Natural History
1 records from Plant (KIWE-PL)
1 records from Plant (GFEI-PL)
1 records from Collection botanique Mulon L. (BOUM)
1 records from svalbardflora.no
1 records from Diversidad vegetal en un gradiente en la Sierra Madre Occidental: flora y vegetación de la Región de San Javier y Yécora, Sonora
1 records from Análisis de la heterogeneidad ambiental y conectividad de las áreas naturales del sur del Valle de México
2 records from Dataflos
2 records from Herbarium of Jyväskylä University Museum
2 records from Herbario COFC de la Universidad de Córdoba: colección histórica
2 records from Museu Darder de Banyoles
2 records from LUSC herbarium - Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina - Herbário Virtual Reflora
2 records from WII Herbarium Dataset
2 records from Registros biológicos  en áreas protegidas obtenidos de documentos impresos
2 records from Inventaire de la flore du Grand Poitiers 2009
2 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (IBK) in China, Guangxi Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences
2 records from The Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Goettingen
2 records from Merseyside BioBank (verified)
2 records from Additional data to the Akrotiri Bioblitz, Cyprus
2 records from EAC herbarium - Universidade Federal do Ceará - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from EAC - Herbário Prisco Bezerra
2 records from Inventaire de la flore des Landes 2015
2 records from Royal Ontario Museum Green Plant Herbarium (TRT)
2 records from Eastern Kentucky University, Ronald L. Jones Herbarium
2 records from Herbarium specimens of CBNA (GAP)
2 records from Flore de Franche-Comté
2 records from Botanical Specimens of Kaizuka City Museum of Natural History (KCMN)
2 records from South Dakota State University, C. A. Taylor Herbarium
2 records from K herbarium - Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from Plant specimens of the Museum of Yamagata University
2 records from Plant specimens of Toyota City Nature Sanctuary (from non-museum circle)
2 records from IPA - Herbário - IPA Dárdano de Andrade Lima
2 records from Herbarium GB, University of Gothenburg
2 records from Merseyside BioBank (unverified)
2 records from Magnoliophyta del Herbario BAB (Instituto de Recursos Biológicos CIRN-INTA)
2 records from Données naturalistes de Paul ROUVEYROL
2 records from Buffalo Society of Natural Sciences Clinton Herbarium
2 records from CIRAD
2 records from Dataset from Herbarium of Endemic Species Research Institute, Taiwan (TAIE) 2021
2 records from SPF - Herbário da Universidade de São Paulo
2 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Herbarium
2 records from Colección Herbario Federico Medem Bogotá - FMB
2 records from WOLL AVH data
2 records from Depuración de la colección y base de datos del Herbario CICY. Fase IV
2 records from HUEFS - Herbario da Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana
2 records from Plant collection Natuurmuseum Brabant, Tilburg
2 records from Vascular plant herbarium (KMN) UiA
2 records from Plant Specimen Database of Tama Forest Science Garden, Forestry and Forest Products Research Institute, Japan
2 records from FBIP: Basic data capture of botanical species collected in the Fernkloof Nature Reserve housed in the Hermanus Botanical Society Herbarium (HER)
2 records from &quot;Flora of Russia&quot; on iNaturalist: a trusted backlog
2 records from herbario Ruiz Leal (IADIZA-CCT CONICET Mendoza): MERL
2 records from Local floras of Russia: a compilative dataset
2 records from Kastikka Small Collections
2 records from LUSC - Herbário de Lages da Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina
2 records from Vascular plant specimens of Omachi Alpine Museum
2 records from An annotated checklist of the Araceae, Leguminosae and Myrtaceae of the department of Boyacá, Colombia
2 records from Actualización de la base de datos del Herbario de la Universidad de Sonora (USON)
2 records from Flora del Parque Nacional Cumbres de Monterrey, Nuevo León, México
2 records from Flora acuática de Querétaro
3 records from Fortalecimiento de las colecciones de ECOSUR. Primera fase (Herbario SCLC)
3 records from ALA species sightings and OzAtlas
3 records from inatura - Erlebnis Naturschau Dornbirn
3 records from Vascular plants collection of Hiratsuka City Museum
3 records from Inventaire de la flore de la Communauté Urbaine de Bordeaux 2009
3 records from Bell Museum plants
3 records from UPCB - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica
3 records from Herbarium specimens, Harmas J.H. Fabre (FABR - Sérignan-du-Comtat) of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
3 records from Bosque Mesófilo de Montaña de México
3 records from Texas Tech University, E. L. Reed Herbarium
3 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Olivier ESCUDER
3 records from IAN herbarium - Embrapa Amazônia Oriental - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
3 records from Seed collection – dead seeds for evaluation and observation purposes
3 records from Herbier E. P. Larchevêque (BOUM)
3 records from Floristic Databases of Mecklenburg-Pomerania - Higher Plants
3 records from CZE National PGR Inventory
3 records from The Bergius Herbarium
3 records from Inventaire de la flore des Landes 2014
3 records from University of Graz, Institute of Plant Sciences - Herbarium GZU
3 records from Inventaire de la flore des pelouses littorales de l&apos;estuaire de la Gironde en Charente-Maritime 2012
3 records from JCT AVH data
3 records from ESA herbarium - Universidade de São Paulo - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
3 records from Database of Vascular Plants of Himalaya
3 records from Contribution to a study of plant cartography in Portugal - degree internship report - Part 1
3 records from University of Azad Jammu and Kashmir Herbarium
3 records from Données naturalistes flore et fonge du Conservatoire des espaces naturels Auvergne saisies avant le 18 février 2019.
3 records from Olga Lakela Herbarium, University of Minnesota Duluth
3 records from Inventario florístico de Tetipac y sus alrededores (Sierra de Taxco)
3 records from Données des réserves naturelles nationales gérées par la Ligue pour la protection des oiseaux (LPO)
3 records from Institut Menorquí d&apos;Estudis. Herbarium Generale Minoricae: HGM
3 records from Herbier de Nouvelle-Calédonie
3 records from Plant specimens of Komatsu City Museum
3 records from Hertfordshire Flora Survey Records 1987-2005
3 records from Herbarium specimens of Association des Naturalistes de la Vallée du Loing (ANVL)
3 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in the research project on long-term vegetation sampling in Napal (Navarra, Spain)
3 records from Sammlung altes Gartenherbar Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
3 records from The 2-5th National Survey on the Natural Environment: Vegetation Survey
3 records from Botanical Research Intitute of Texas
4 records from herbario
4 records from CPERC Combined Dataset
4 records from Flora de los Parques Ecológicos Distritales Humedales de Bogotá D.C.
4 records from Colorado State University Herbarium
4 records from Gunma Museum of Natural History, Vascular Plant Specimen
4 records from Herbario de Universidad de Murcia: MUB
4 records from Floristic Study in Orchards - Mafra and Torres Vedras, Portugal
4 records from Berea College, Ralph L. Thompson Herbarium
4 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Herbarium Tubingense
4 records from Collections of Bioclass, school #179, Moscow
4 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in the research project on dark diversity of plant communities in the centre-east of Navarra (Spain)
4 records from Estudio florístico de la Sierra de Pachuca, Hidalgo, México
4 records from Herbier Flora selecta exsiccata publié par Ch. MAGNIER (BOUM)
4 records from ESA - Herbário da Escola Superior de Agricultura Luiz de Queiroz
4 records from Herbarium of Shinshu University
4 records from WildNet - Queensland Wildlife Data
4 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares de la Asociación BIGA para el estudio del patrimonio natural de Galicia: FBIGA
4 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares del Museo Municipal de Ciencias Naturales &apos;Lorenzo Scaglia&apos;  MMPEAAH
4 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
4 records from FLOR - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica da Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina
4 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Economic Botany Collection Specimens
4 records from B herbarium - Botanischer Garten und Botanisches Museum Berlin-Dahlem Herbarium - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
4 records from Colección general del plantas vasculares del Herbario JBB
4 records from CESJ - Herbário Leopoldo Krieger
4 records from Herbarium areqvipense (HUSA)
4 records from Base de datos de la distribución de la flora de la Reserva de la Biosfera Tehuacán-Cuicatlán
4 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
4 records from University of Lethbridge Herbarium (LEA)
4 records from National Trust Species Records
4 records from TB Lee Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection Phase II
4 records from Estonian University of Life Sciences Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Vascular Plant Herbarium
4 records from Dutch Vegetation Database
4 records from Jeu de données convention FEGVE-SPN-2012-2016
4 records from Dorset Sites of Nature Conservation Interest (SNCI) species records 2000-2008
4 records from Plant (NSMK-PL)
5 records from University of Sindh Jamshoro Herbarium
5 records from Kathryn Kalmbach Herbarium
5 records from Vascular Plant Specimens of the RYU Herbarium (Faculty of Science, University of the Ryukyus)
5 records from MO herbarium -  Missouri Botanical Garden - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
5 records from Canberra Nature Map
5 records from Vascular plant herbarium, UiT Tromsø Museum
5 records from IRAI - Herbário do Parque da Ciência Newton Freire Maia
5 records from Environmental Monitoring Database Species data 1987 to 2015
5 records from FLOTROP, a massive contribution to plant diversity data for open ecosystems in Tropical Africa.
5 records from DEMNA-DNE : Exotic plant occurrences in Wallonia
5 records from Atlas des plantes vasculaires de Lorraine
5 records from CNS AVH data
5 records from Collection botanique Le Grand A. (BOUM)
5 records from MBM herbarium - Museu Botânico Municipal \ Curitiba - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
5 records from UKSBA Cyprus - Quadrats 2015-2017
6 records from Vascular Plant Collection of Natural History Museum and Institute, Chiba
6 records from Plant specimens of Horaiji-san Museum of Natural History Kichi T. collection
6 records from HAS - Herbário Alarich Rudolf Holger Schultz
6 records from SysTax - Herbaria
6 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
6 records from IAC - Herbário do Instituto Agronômico de Campinas
6 records from Sistematización de la colección entomológica y actualización de la colección del herbario CHIP del Instituto de Historia Natural y Ecología (IHNE), Chiapas (Plantas)
6 records from Inventaire de la flore du PNRLG 2018 (Landes)
6 records from Plantas de La Frontera (ecorregión 12.1.1.1), e inventario florístico del Rancho El Aribabi, municipio de Imuris, Sonora
6 records from Inventaire de la flore par le CBN Sud-Atlantique sur le PNRLG 2007-2008
6 records from flora&amp;fauna(NIBR)2019
6 records from Weed and native flora data for the Swan Coastal Plain
6 records from SEWBReC Vascular Plants (South East Wales)
6 records from FKSE-Herbarium of Faculty of Symbiotic Systems Science, Fukushima University, Japan
6 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (algas, frutos y semillas, hongos, líquenes, xiloteca)
7 records from Universität Salzburg
7 records from melu_avh
7 records from Oklahoma Vascular Plants Database Provider
7 records from Dr Mary Gillham Archive Project
7 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants recovery after a fire event in a mixed oak forest in Nazar (Navarra, Spain). PhD project, L. Alberdi
7 records from Floristic Study in Orchards - Beira Interior, Portugal
7 records from BRERC Notable Species records within the last 10 years
7 records from Herbarium specimens of the Muséum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle d&apos;Autun (AUT)
7 records from Muséum d’histoire naturelle de Grenoble
7 records from Herbario Museo de La Salle Bogotá (BOG)
7 records from Flora of the Korean Peninsula Phase II
7 records from Actualización y depuración de la base de datos del Herbario del Instituto de Ecología, AC, Centro Regional del Bajío. Fase 2
7 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
7 records from Flora vascular de la Sierra de las Candelas, Municipio Jerez de García Salinas, Zacatecas, México
8 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
8 records from Hortus Botanicus Sollerensis Herbarium (FBonafè)
8 records from Plant Specimens of The Shimane Nature Museum of Mt. Sanbe
8 records from Inventaire de la flore des Landes 2016
8 records from Digitalización de la colección científica del Herbario de Querétaro &quot;Dr. Jerzy Rzedowski&quot; QMEX
8 records from Inventaire de la flore de Dordogne 2016
8 records from Spermatophyte collection of Himeji City Science Museum
8 records from Carnet B Centre - lot 2012
9 records from Staatliches Museum für Naturkunde Stuttgart, Herbarium
9 records from Plant specimens depodited in Osaka Museum of Natural History, Japan
9 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
9 records from CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino
9 records from NY herbarium - The New York Botanical Garden - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
9 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in Pamplona and surroundings (Navarra, Spain). Undergraduate thesis, R. Mayo
9 records from NatureShare
9 records from Kastikka Literature Sources
9 records from Alien plant presence dataset from the point-radius plot surveys in 2010-2015 in Taiwan
9 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
9 records from WIKTROP - Weed Identification and Knowledge in the Tropical and Mediterranean areas
9 records from SMDB - Santa Maria Departamento de Biologia
9 records from Genus Medicago (Fabaceae) in CSBG Herbarium collections (NS, NSK)
9 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
9 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
10 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
10 records from Données naturalistes de Pierre DUFRENE
10 records from BODATSA: Botanical Collections
10 records from The French Collection of Medicago truncatula
10 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
10 records from Some Plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1900 to 1950
10 records from RNF - Données de la Fédération des Réserves Catalanes
10 records from Royal BC Museum - Herbarium (V)
10 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
10 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2014
10 records from Natural History Museum Maastricht (NL) - Herbarium
11 records from Fairchild Tropical Botanic Garden (FTG)
11 records from Plant specimens in the Museum of Nature and Human Activities, Hyogo Prefecture, Japan
11 records from TUR Vascular plant collections of the Turku University, Herbarium generale
11 records from Wikiplantbase #Italia
11 records from Biodiversitätsdatenbank Salzburg
11 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2013
11 records from MPUC - Herbário do Museu da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
11 records from Base de datos del Municipio General Heliodoro Castillo, Guerrero (120. Sierra Madre del Sur)
11 records from Tracheophyta collection of Biodiversity Center of Japan, Ministry of the Environment
11 records from FBIP: Great Escarpment Biodiversity Research Programme data mobilisation
11 records from PRECIS (KwaZulu-Natal Herbarium)
11 records from Inventaire de la flore des Landes 2017
11 records from Inventaire de la flore de Dordogne 2018
11 records from Muséum des Volcans
11 records from CONN
11 records from Observations.be - Non-native species occurrences in Wallonia, Belgium
11 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
12 records from Vascular Plant Collection - University of Washington Herbarium (WTU)
12 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla, SEV-Historico
12 records from MISS_DC_01MAR2006
12 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
12 records from Herbario de la Universidad Pública de Navarra, Pamplona: UPNA-H
12 records from Banco de datos florísticos del Herbario CHAP
12 records from UKSBA Cyprus - Habitat Samples, 2019
12 records from MCCC - Mendocino College Coast Center Herbarium
12 records from Herbario del Jardín Botánico-Histórico La Concepción: HBC
12 records from Institut Menorquí d&apos;Estudis. Colección Histórica de Rodríguez Femenías, Herbarium Generale Minoricae: HGM-Femenias
12 records from University of Jena, Herbarium Haussknecht - Herbarium JE
12 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2013
12 records from The digitization of plant specimens of NTU
12 records from Biodiversity4all Research-Grade Observations
12 records from 500,000 plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1950 to 1999
12 records from Muséum d’histoire naturelle du Mans
12 records from Vascular Plant Specimens of Yamagata Prefectural Museum
13 records from Herbarium of Namur
13 records from Herbarium specimens of the Muséum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle of Aix-en-Provence (AIX)
13 records from Herbarium Specimens of Bonin and Ryukyu Islands
13 records from R - Herbário do Museu Nacional
13 records from Fusión y actualización de las bases de datos del Herbario de la Facultad de Ciencias, UNAM (FCME), Guerrero
13 records from United Herbaria of the University and ETH Zurich
13 records from University of Vienna, Institute for Botany - Herbarium WU
14 records from Herbarium (UNA)
14 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
14 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
14 records from Actualización e incremento de la base de datos del Herbario de la Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla
14 records from Vascular plant specimens of Toyama Science Museum
14 records from Welsh BSBI data (ex-VPDB dataset) at hectad resolution
15 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum Görlitz (GLM)
15 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2016
15 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
15 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
15 records from H.A. Stephens Herbarium
15 records from Université d&apos;Aix-Marseille
16 records from Herbario EMMA. Herbario de la Escuela Técnica Superior de Ingenieros de Montes. UPM
16 records from Vascular Plant Specimens of Kochi Prefectural Makino Botanical Garden
16 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2012
16 records from Flore Franco-Belge
16 records from Earth Guardians Weekly Feed
16 records from Vascular plant records verified via iRecord
16 records from Rutgers University, Chrysler Herbarium
16 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
16 records from Inventaire de la flore de Dordogne 2015
16 records from Occurrence Data of Vascular Plants collected or compiled for the Flora of Bavaria
16 records from Colección de Fabales del Museo Botánico CORD - IMBIV
17 records from Vascular plant specimens of National Museum of Nature and Science (TNS)
17 records from Vascular plant specimens of Nagano Environmental Conservation Research Institute, Nagano Prefecture
17 records from Charles University Prague - Herbarium PRC
17 records from Salinity Action Plan Flora Survey
17 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - A. Danin&apos;s point database
18 records from Herbarium Specimens of Museum of Nature and Human Activities, Hyogo Pref., Japan
18 records from Precis Plant Data
18 records from LERN Records
18 records from Flore d&apos;Ille-et-Vilaine
18 records from INSDC Sequences
18 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2017 - Littoral
18 records from Inventaire de la flore des Landes 2012 (Chalosse et Tursan)
19 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
19 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
19 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
19 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
20 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
20 records from PACA-AGP - Herbarium Anchieta
20 records from Manchester Museum, University of Manchester, Botany Collection
20 records from Inventaire de la flore de Dordogne 2017
21 records from Universitat de Girona: HGI-Cormophyta
21 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
21 records from Clemson University Herbarium
21 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (HIB) in China, Wuhan Botanical Garden, Chinese Academy of Sciences
21 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
21 records from Catálogo electrónico de especímenes depositados en el Herbario de la Universidad de Texas en Austin, Fase IV (Ejemplaresimagenes)
22 records from PUA - Pacific Union College Hebarium
23 records from Inventaire de la flore de Bordeaux Métropole 2013
23 records from Wikiplantbase #Liguria
23 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
23 records from DNA AVH data
24 records from Vascular Plants Collection of Sagamihara City Museum
24 records from Herbario Nacional Colombiano (COL)
24 records from University of Tartu Natural History Museum and Botanical Garden Botanical Collections
24 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
24 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2015
25 records from flora &amp; fauna(NIBR)
25 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
26 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
26 records from Vascular Plant Specimen database of Kanagawa Prefectural Museum of Natural History
26 records from Inventaire de la flore des Landes 2018
26 records from Instituto de Botánica Darwinion
26 records from Oskarshamn herbarium (OHN)
27 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2015
27 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
27 records from Isle of Wight Notable Species
27 records from ICN herbarium - Universidade Federal do Rio Grande Do Sul - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
27 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
28 records from Scottish SNH-funded BSBI records
28 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
28 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2018
28 records from Données Vigie-Flore
30 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Almería
30 records from Vascular Plant Collection
30 records from Digitalización y sistematización de las colecciones biológicas del INECOL (Herbario)
30 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2018
30 records from Puntos de presencia en Baja California (Botany)
30 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2018
31 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO-Briof
31 records from University of Florida Herbarium (FLAS)
31 records from Wikiplantbase Sicilia
31 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2014
31 records from Masaryk University - Herbarium BRNU
31 records from Données Herbiers de l&apos;Université de Strasbourg
32 records from The Himalayan Uplands Plant database (HUP Version 1)
32 records from TAXA - Flore et habitats naturels de Franche-Comté
32 records from FSC - Fresno State Herbarium
33 records from Herbarium Specimens of Tokushima Prefectural Museum, Japan
33 records from Allan Herbarium (CHR)
33 records from Plant (JNHM-PL)
34 records from Universidad del Paí­s Vasco/EHU, Bilbao: Herbario BIO
34 records from Botany (UPS)
34 records from Herbier de Strasbourg
35 records from Aranzadi Zientzi Elkartea
35 records from Muséum d&apos;histoire naturelle de Nîmes
35 records from Vascular plant herbarium TRH, NTNU University Museum
35 records from Données de la flore d’Alsace (SBA)
35 records from BRERC species records from all years at full resolution excluding Notable Species within the last 10 years
36 records from Herbario de la Universitat de les Illes Balears
37 records from Données naturalistes de Thomas GAILLARD
37 records from Herbarium Horti Botanici Pisani (PI), Sistema Museale di Ateneo, Università di Pisa
37 records from ICN - Herbário do Instituto de Ciências Naturais
37 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2018
38 records from Herbarium of Taiwan Forestry Research Institute
38 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
39 records from NE AVH data
39 records from Botanical Collections of the Åbo Akademi (TUR-A)
39 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
40 records from Plant Specimens of Kurashiki Museum of Natural History
40 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
40 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario de la Universidad de Granada.
41 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO
41 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2017
41 records from Suffolk Biodiversity Information Service (SBIS) Dataset
43 records from Computarización del Herbario ENCB. Fase I (Base de datos de los ejemplares del Valle de México)
43 records from Inventaire permanent de la flore du massif armoricain
43 records from Observations floristiques floutées issues de la base de données flore du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
43 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB
44 records from Universidad de Navarra, Herbarium: PAMP-Vascular Plants
44 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2017
44 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
46 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, UiB
48 records from Herbarium Erlangense
48 records from FLORIVON
49 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2015
50 records from Collections and observation data National Museum of Natural History Luxembourg
51 records from Etapa final de la captura y catalogación del Herbario del Instituto de Ecología, A. C., Centro Regional del Bajío
51 records from Tasmanian Natural Values Atlas
51 records from Other BSBI Scottish data up to 2015
52 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
52 records from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium
53 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Ciencias Biológicas de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MACB)
53 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2016
53 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
54 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
55 records from CeDoc de Biodiversitat Vegetal: BCN-Cormophyta
55 records from VIT Herbarium - Vascular Plants (The Natural History Museum of Alava)
55 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - Israeli Gene Bank
55 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2017
56 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2014
57 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
57 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
61 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
61 records from HO AVH data
65 records from Inventaire de la flore des Pyrénées-Atlantiques 2007-2008 - Littoral
66 records from Cartographie des Leguminosae (Fabaceae) en France
69 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
70 records from Observations floristiques issues de la base de données du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
70 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
70 records from Some Plant Specimens from KUN, IBSC, NAS  Herbarium in China from 1900 to 1950
71 records from INRAE Villa Thuret
72 records from Catalogue of the plant communities of Madeira and Porto Santo
72 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2016
75 records from NIEK_NES
77 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
77 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
77 records from LSU Shirley C. Tucker Herbarium at Louisiana State University - Vascular Plants
80 records from Herbario ABH (Universidad de Alicante)
81 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
81 records from Catálogo Florístico Histórico de Navarra. Gobierno de Navarra
85 records from Conservation Atlas Surveys
85 records from EDP Foz-Tua: Macrophytes – Ecological Monitoring Program [2011-2015]
89 records from Herbario HSS Finca La Orden-Valdesequera (CICYTEX). Junta de Extremadura
93 records from Base de datos de plantas vasculares del País Vasco: ARAN-EH
93 records from MGC Herbarium of University of Malaga (Spain): MGC-Cormof dataset
94 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
96 records from Malezas introducidas en México
97 records from Plant
97 records from Données acquises dans le cadre de l&apos;activité du bureau d&apos;étude BIOTOPE (1994 - 2013)
98 records from Herbarium of Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Extremadura (Spain)
103 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
106 records from Flora of Worcestershire
108 records from Wikiplantbase #Sardegna
113 records from PERTH AVH data
114 records from Jardín Botánico de Córdoba: Herbarium COA
114 records from Carnet en Ligne
115 records from Florabank1 - A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in the northern part of Belgium (Flanders and the Brussels Capital region)
116 records from Segetal flora of Italy
117 records from Flora von Deutschland (Phanerogamen)
120 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares de la Universidad de Salamanca: SALA
120 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - INPA database
120 records from BRI AVH data
122 records from Artportalen (Swedish Species Observation System)
124 records from Herbarium of University of Coimbra (COI )
124 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
129 records from Swiss National Databank of Vascular Plants
132 records from Pl@ntNet observations
132 records from Waarnemingen.be - Non-native plant occurrences in Flanders and the Brussels Capital Region, Belgium
135 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
138 records from Instituto Pirenaico de Ecología-CSIC: Herbarium JACA
141 records from Plant Resources Center
141 records from PRECIS
142 records from Herbário João de Carvalho e Vasconcellos, I.S.A./U.L.
146 records from Données d&apos;occurrences Espèces issues de l&apos;inventaire des ZNIEFF
156 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
167 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
174 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB, CSIC-Ajuntament de Barcelona), BC-Plantae
175 records from Phytochorologie des départements français
179 records from NSW AVH data
184 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL)
189 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
190 records from Herbario COFC de la Universidad de Córdoba: colección general de plantas vasculares
191 records from Wikiplantbase #Toscana
195 records from Pl@ntNet automatically identified occurrences
205 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
205 records from CANB AVH data
231 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
233 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
237 records from Israel Nature and Parks Authority
246 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium: Herbarium Generale
252 records from Herbarium Willing at Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
266 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
268 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
284 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
289 records from MEL AVH data
296 records from BioGIS - Vascular plants - A. Danin&apos;s grid database
311 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
322 records from Observation.org, Nature data from around the World
327 records from Flora-On: occurrence data of the flora of mainland Portugal
337 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
345 records from Observations du Conservatoire botanique national du Bassin parisien.
377 records from EDP Baixo Sabor: Construction and Reservoir Filling Phases – Vascular Flora and Habitats: species from prioritary conservation habitats - [2010-2014]
377 records from Quaid-i-Azam University Herbarium
381 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
406 records from EDP Foz-Tua: Vascular Flora and Habitats – Ecological and Complementary Measures Monitoring Programs – Construction Phase II [2015-2016] and Flooding Phase [2016-2017]
409 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla
414 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
468 records from Université Lyon 1
476 records from Bioversity Collecting Mission Database
490 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
541 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
592 records from Australasian Virtual Herbarium (AVH) data from the State Herbarium of South Australia (AD)
676 records from Flore du Bassin parisien (CBNBP)
701 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
796 records from EDP Foz-Tua: Vascular Flora – Ecological and Complentary Measures Monitoring Programs – Contruction Phase I [2012-2014]
817 records from Azorean Biodiversity Portal
890 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
935 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
942 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Anthos. Sistema de Información de las Plantas de España
968 records from BSBI data from several English counties, up to 2015
1024 records from FloraCAT: Banco de datos de los cormófitos de Cataluña
1111 records from Sistema de Información de la vegetación Ibérica y Macaronésica
1169 records from Banco de Datos de la Biodiversidad de la Comunitat Valenciana
1253 records from Localización de táxones botánicos de interés para la identificación de hábitats de la REDIAM (Secretaría General de Medio Ambiente, Agua y Cambio Climático)
1291 records from Cartografía de vegetación a escala de detalle 1:10.000 de la masa forestal de Andalucía
1513 records from Observations floristiques - plateforme SINP régionale SILENE   PACA
1520 records from SA Flora (BDBSA)
1730 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
1921 records from The System-wide Information Network for Genetic Resources (SINGER)
2713 records from Victorian Biodiversity Atlas
3394 records from INPN - Données flore des CBN agrégées par la FCBN
7206 records from NSW BioNet Atlas
9534 records from A global database for the distributions of crop wild relatives</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T03:17:17Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.tj9zn7">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.tj9zn7</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130533-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
