<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.varh2v"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130656-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.varh2v</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Euphorbia esula L.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Leiner-Herbar Konstanz
1 records from Korean Ethnobotany Database
1 records from Herbario EMMA. Herbario de la Escuela Técnica Superior de Ingenieros de Montes. UPM
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla, SEV-Historico
1 records from Herbario HSS Finca La Orden-Valdesequera (CICYTEX). Junta de Extremadura
1 records from Botanic Garden of the Finnish Museum of Natural History
1 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
1 records from The Erysiphales Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
1 records from The Erysiphales Collection at the University Halle-Wittenberg
1 records from Flore de l&apos;Ain
1 records from Spermatophyta specimens of Iwate Prefectural Museum
1 records from Vascular Plants Collection of Sagamihara City Museum
1 records from Vascular plants of south-central China
1 records from Clémence Lortet herbarium
1 records from Schulgarten Huttenheim (Philippsburg/Baden)
1 records from Biologische Station im Kreis Wesel
1 records from GEO-Hauptveranstaltung (Duisburg)
1 records from Sudeniederung (Amt Neuhaus), Landkreis Lüneburg
1 records from Données naturalistes de Cyrille DELIRY
1 records from Stadtgebiet (Dannenberg)
1 records from 2019_biodiversity_cooperation_investigation
1 records from Laubenheimer Bodenheimer Ried - von Stromtalwiesen und Flutrasen
1 records from Banco de Datos de la Biodiversidad de la Comunitat Valenciana
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad Pública de Navarra, Pamplona: UPNA-H
1 records from Species recordings from the Danish National portal Arter.dk
1 records from Plant of Folklore (KIDR-PL)
1 records from CSUSB - California State University San Bernardino
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2016
1 records from Occurrence data from various smaller projects in Norway
1 records from Berlin-Brandenburg Plant Collection 2006
1 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Olivier ESCUDER
1 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
1 records from LERN Records
1 records from SBT-Living
1 records from The Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Goettingen
1 records from FURB - Herbário Dr. Roberto Miguel Klein
1 records from Vascular plants of grasslands in Central Forest Nature Reserve (Tver Oblast, Russia)
1 records from Biodiversity of the lower part of the Desna River basin
1 records from Herbario del Jardín Botánico-Histórico La Concepción: HBC
1 records from Type herbarium, Göttingen (GOET)
1 records from Family Geraniaceae in CSBG SB RAS herbarium collections (NS, NSK)
1 records from Flore d&apos;Ille-et-Vilaine
1 records from Herbier Flora selecta exsiccata publié par Ch. MAGNIER (BOUM)
1 records from Herbier E. P. Larchevêque (BOUM)
1 records from Institut Menorquí d&apos;Estudis. Colección Histórica de Rodríguez Femenías, Herbarium Generale Minoricae: HGM-Femenias
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 46
1 records from Chapter 7: Linnaean Plant Names and their Types (part E)
1 records from MPUC - Herbário do Museu da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
1 records from &quot;Flora des Gouvernements Wladimir&quot; (Fleroff, 1902): georeferenced records
1 records from Observations faune et flore du Parc national des Écrins
1 records from Invasive Plant Atlas of the MidSouth (IPAMS)
1 records from Herbarium of University of Białystok - Vascular Plants
1 records from Korean Peninsula Flora
1 records from BoBO - Botanic Garden and Botanical Museum Berlin Observations
1 records from Conventions d’étude sur la biodiversité française – Partenariats du Service du patrimoine naturel
1 records from Anymals+plants - Citizen Science Data
1 records from Typotheca of the higher vascular plants stored in M.G. Popov Herbarium (NSK) at the Central Siberian botanical garden SB RAS
1 records from FURB herbarium - Universidade Regional de Blumenau - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
1 records from Herbier Boreal Confluence (BOUM)
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 30
1 records from Instituto de Botánica Darwinion
1 records from Species biodiversity transnational geo-database - IMPRECO Project
1 records from UFMT - Herbário UFMT
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Limoges university (LIMO)
1 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Anaïs MAS
1 records from Modernisation des ZNIEFF du PnrL
1 records from Vascular plant records verified via iRecord
1 records from Weber State University Herbarium
1 records from Données naturalistes flore et fonge du Conservatoire des espaces naturels Auvergne saisies avant le 18 février 2019.
1 records from Données naturalistes de Cyril EPICOCO
1 records from Données naturalistes de Paul ROUVEYROL
1 records from National Finnish butterfly monitoring scheme (NAFI) (NAFI)
1 records from CHAS Botany Collection (Arctos)
1 records from Collection d&apos;animaux marins et plantes du Museum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle de Nice
1 records from Berlin-Brandenburg Plant Collection 2005
1 records from CNS AVH data
1 records from Digitization of plant specimens from Rhoen and Vogelsberg (FLAD)
1 records from Isle of Man historical wildlife records 1995 to 1999
1 records from Herbario MAIA, colección Flora Forestal del INIA-CIFOR
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2018
1 records from Inventaire du legs Thénard (Bourgogne)
1 records from NEON Biorepository Terrestrial Plant Collection (Herbarium Vouchers)
1 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2014
1 records from BRFC Black Rock Forest Consortium Herbarium
1 records from Sbp-BioBlitz2017_60years-BiodiversityData
1 records from Manchester Museum, University of Manchester, Botany Collection
1 records from Collection botanique Le Grand A. (BOUM)
1 records from ALCB - Herbário Alexandre Leal Costa
1 records from Herbarium GAT
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - Alaska, United States
1 records from DBG Tissue and DNA Bank
1 records from Truppenübungsplatz Panzerkaserne Böblingen
1 records from Wangerooge
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Dordogne 2015
1 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
1 records from Sudeniederung (Amt Neuhaus)
1 records from Schatzinsel Wangerooge
1 records from Données Vigie-Flore
1 records from ALCB herbarium - Universidade Federal da Bahia - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Living plant collection of Meise Botanic Garden
1 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
1 records from The 2-5th National Survey on the Natural Environment: Vegetation Survey
1 records from Données naturalistes de Philippe GOURDAIN
1 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
1 records from Artenvielfalt am Eich-Gimbsheimer Altrhein
1 records from FKSE-Herbarium of Faculty of Symbiotic Systems Science, Fukushima University, Japan
1 records from Plant (KOBG_PL)
1 records from Plant (MNHM-PL)
1 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
1 records from BRERC species records from all years at full resolution excluding Notable Species within the last 10 years
2 records from Herbario ABH (Universidad de Alicante)
2 records from DAO Herbarium Type Specimens
2 records from Plant Specimens of Kurashiki Museum of Natural History
2 records from Flora exsiccata Bavarica
2 records from inatura - Erlebnis Naturschau Dornbirn
2 records from Plant specimens depodited in Osaka Museum of Natural History, Japan
2 records from Photographs of higher plants, mosses, fungi, lichens, and algae
2 records from Königstetten
2 records from A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in southern part of Yaroslavl Oblast, Russia
2 records from P herbarium - Muséum national d’histoire naturelle, Paris - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from Perchtoldsdorfer Heide
2 records from Vascular Plants, Museum of Archaeology, University of Stavanger
2 records from University of Florida Herbarium (FLAS)
2 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in Ribera Occidental de Navarra (Spain). PhD project, L. Garde
2 records from Eastern Kentucky University, Ronald L. Jones Herbarium
2 records from NRW Regional Data: South East Wales Non-sensitive species
2 records from Wikiplantbase #Liguria
2 records from The Bergius Herbarium
2 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
2 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
2 records from Welsh BSBI data (ex-VPDB dataset) at hectad resolution
2 records from Observations floristiques issues de la base de données flore du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
2 records from Inventaire de la flore de Charente-Maritime 2015
2 records from Clemson University Herbarium
2 records from Pl@ntNet automatically identified occurrences
2 records from CANB AVH data
2 records from Herbario Nacional Colombiano (COL)
2 records from Urban flora of Kostanay region (Republic of Kazakhstan)
2 records from Data on macrophyte diversity in rivers and streams of the Vologda Region and several other regions of Russia
2 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Palynology Collection
2 records from B herbarium - Botanischer Garten und Botanisches Museum Berlin-Dahlem Herbarium - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium
2 records from CESJ - Herbário Leopoldo Krieger
2 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2018
2 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
2 records from Collection botanique Jaubert et Saul (BOUM)
2 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2014
2 records from HO AVH data
2 records from Foreign Asia herbarium collection in CSBG (NS)
2 records from MEL AVH data
2 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2015
2 records from Plant specimens of Horaiji-san Museum of Natural History
2 records from Biosphärenpark Wienerwald - Wiener Steinhofgründe
2 records from &quot;Laubenheimer Bodenheimer Ried&quot; - von Stromtalwiesen und Flutrasen
2 records from Sammlung altes Gartenherbar Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
2 records from Colección de Laurales, Liliales, Lycopodiales, Magnoliales y Malpighiales del Museo Botánico CORD - IMBIV
2 records from Biosphärenpark Wienerwald - Pfaffstätten
3 records from Botanical Garden Collection
3 records from Herbarium of Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Extremadura (Spain)
3 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
3 records from BLM - National Landscape Monitoring Framework - Plants
3 records from MISS_DC_01MAR2006
3 records from Vascular Plant Specimen database of Kanagawa Prefectural Museum of Natural History
3 records from Pittsburg State University, Theodore M. Sperry Herbarium
3 records from Rotherham Biological Records Centre - Non-sensitive Records from all taxonomic groups
3 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (LBG) in China, Lushan Botanical Garden, Jiangxi and Chinese Academy of Sciences
3 records from Données naturalistes de Thomas GAILLARD
3 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
3 records from Florient - a database dealing with historic wild plant occurrences
3 records from PlutoF platform reference-based occurrences
3 records from BHCB - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais
3 records from Lajitietokeskus/FinBIF - Notebook, general observations
3 records from E. C. Smith Herbarium (ACAD)
3 records from Herbarium GB, University of Gothenburg
3 records from Kherson State University herbarium (KHER), Department of Botany
3 records from Flora of the Stołowe Mts.
3 records from University of Graz, Institute of Plant Sciences - Herbarium GZU
3 records from The Vascular Plants Collection of the Regensburgische Botanische Gesellschaft
3 records from Herbarium specimens of the Muséum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle d&apos;Autun (AUT)
3 records from Mohonk Preserve Historical Observational Biodiversity Data
3 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
3 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium at the Kandalaksha Strict Nature Reserve (KAND), Russia
3 records from Plant observations from Białowieża National Park
3 records from NINA Artskart data
3 records from Herbarium specimens of Association des Naturalistes de la Vallée du Loing (ANVL)
3 records from SEWBReC Vascular Plants (South East Wales)
3 records from Tiroler Landesmuseum Ferdinandeum
3 records from NatureServe Network Species Occurrence Data
4 records from Herbario COFC de la Universidad de Córdoba: colección general de plantas vasculares
4 records from Herbarium Hamburgense
4 records from Herbarium of the Prioksko-Terrasnyi Biosphere Reserve
4 records from Texas Tech University, E. L. Reed Herbarium
4 records from RNF - Données du Conservatoire d&apos;espaces naturel Centre
4 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - United States (Contiguous) V2.0
4 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
4 records from Herbarium Erlangense
4 records from University of Jena, Herbarium Haussknecht - Herbarium JE
4 records from Relevés of Main Vegetation Types of the Prioksko-Terrasnyi Biosphere Reserve (2021)
4 records from Rare vascular plant species of Transbaikalia (Republic of Buryatia and Zabaikalsky Kray), Russia
4 records from Vascular Plants, Field notes, Agder naturmuseum (KMN)
4 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
4 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
4 records from niek_2022
4 records from FLORUS: miscellaneous records
4 records from Tallinn Botanic Garden
4 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
4 records from Urban floras of Central Urals
5 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO
5 records from Botanical Museum, Copenhagen. Database of type specimens
5 records from Données naturalistes de CERCOPE (Jean-Louis PRATZ)
5 records from Classic localities of endemic vascular plants from the Western Balkans
5 records from MGC Herbarium of University of Malaga (Spain): MGC-Cormof dataset
5 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO-Briof
5 records from vegetation releves on grassland gridplots 2007-2009
5 records from vegetation releves on grassland gridplots in 2007
5 records from Michigan State University Herbarium Vascular Plants
5 records from Universidad de Navarra, Herbarium: PAMP-Vascular Plants
5 records from SJSU - Carl W. Sharsmith Herbarium, San Jose State University
5 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
5 records from Dutch Foundation for Applied Water Research (STOWA) - Limnodata Neerlandica
5 records from CSLA - Cal State LA Herbarium
5 records from Muséum des Volcans
5 records from Observations.be - Non-native species occurrences in Wallonia, Belgium
5 records from mabik_tp
5 records from TKM Herbarium: Tula Oblast collections of vascular plants
6 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
6 records from Vascular plants from European Russia in the CSBG SB RAS Digital herbarium
6 records from Base de datos de plantas vasculares del País Vasco: ARAN-EH
6 records from Database of Native Plants in Taiwan
6 records from Herbarium specimens, Harmas J.H. Fabre (FABR - Sérignan-du-Comtat) of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
6 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
6 records from Muséum d&apos;histoire naturelle de Nîmes
6 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
6 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
6 records from Données naturalistes de GAULTIER Cyrille
6 records from Bruce Bennett Herbarium (BABY)
6 records from Buffalo Society of Natural Sciences Clinton Herbarium
6 records from BioFokus
6 records from Flora of Seymskiy Regional Landscape Park
6 records from Muséum d’histoire naturelle du Mans
6 records from &quot;Flora of Russia&quot; on iNaturalist: a trusted backlog
6 records from Butler University Friesner Herbarium (BUT)
7 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
7 records from Plant specimens of Horaiji-san Museum of Natural History Kichi T. collection
7 records from Collections of Bioclass, school #179, Moscow
7 records from Wikiplantbase #Italia
7 records from Estonian Nature Observations Database
7 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
7 records from Species of plants and fungi in the middle part of the Hirskyi Tikych river basin
7 records from Central Michigan University Herbarium
7 records from specimen_records_nefi
7 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
7 records from flora&amp;fauna(NIBR)2019
7 records from MBM herbarium - Museu Botânico Municipal \ Curitiba - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
7 records from Université d&apos;Aix-Marseille
7 records from Twelve local floras of European Russia
7 records from Plant (JNHM-PL)
7 records from Flora-On: occurrence data of the flora of mainland Portugal
8 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
8 records from Aranzadi Zientzi Elkartea
8 records from Herbário João de Carvalho e Vasconcellos, I.S.A./U.L.
8 records from Herbarium of Umeå University (UME)
8 records from Herbarium of University of Coimbra (COI )
8 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
8 records from Vascular plants of old cemeteries of Lower Dnipro region (Southern Ukraine)
8 records from University of Lethbridge Herbarium (LEA)
8 records from UAM Herbarium (ALA), Vascular Plant Collection (Arctos)
8 records from Mongolian Plant (MMNH-PL)
8 records from Données Herbiers de l&apos;Université de Strasbourg
9 records from Ibaraki Nature Museum, Vascular Plants collection
9 records from Données naturalistes de Damien AVRIL
9 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
9 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Ciencias Biológicas de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MACB)
9 records from Sistema de Información de la vegetación Ibérica y Macaronésica
9 records from Finds of species of animals, fungi and plants from particular territories of Podesinnia
9 records from LSU Shirley C. Tucker Herbarium at Louisiana State University - Vascular Plants
9 records from Fungus Collections at Staatliches Museum für Naturkunde Karlsruhe (Herbarium KR)
9 records from Cartografía de vegetación a escala de detalle 1:10.000 de la masa forestal de Andalucía
10 records from Jardín Botánico de Córdoba: Herbarium COA
10 records from FloVegSI - Floristical and fitocenological database of ZRC SAZU
10 records from ArtenFinder
10 records from VegetWeb - Repositorium von Vegetationsaufnahmen
10 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
10 records from 2019_nsmk_biodiversity_pl_8750
10 records from Central Siberian Botanical Garden Herbarium (NS, NSK)
10 records from Herbarium specimens of Jardins botaniques and Conservatoire Botanique of Nancy (NCY)
10 records from Localización de táxones botánicos de interés para la identificación de hábitats de la REDIAM (Secretaría General de Medio Ambiente, Agua y Cambio Climático)
10 records from 2019_nsmk_pl_3
10 records from Herbarium Horti Botanici Pisani (PI), Sistema Museale di Ateneo, Università di Pisa
10 records from TB Lee Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection Phase II
10 records from Données d&apos;occurrence Espèces issues de la base Natura 2000 : espèces d&apos;intérêt communautaire et autres espèces remarquables renseignées dans les FSD
10 records from Catálogo Florístico Histórico de Navarra. Gobierno de Navarra
11 records from Vascular Herbarium, NMBU
11 records from Données faune, flore et fonge du Conservatoire des espaces naturels de Picardie
11 records from Phytocenoteca of the laboratory of ecosystem theory (Plants)
11 records from RNF - Association Loiret Nature Environnement
11 records from Flora of the Korean Peninsula
11 records from Naturhistorisches Museum Mainz, Herbarium Oesau
11 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
12 records from Staatliches Museum für Naturkunde Stuttgart, Herbarium
12 records from Botany Division, Yale Peabody Museum
12 records from Dr Mary Gillham Archive Project
12 records from VIT Herbarium - Vascular Plants (The Natural History Museum of Alava)
12 records from Flora of Worcestershire
12 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
12 records from Nijmegen Natural History Museum (NL) - Herbarium
12 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
13 records from Herbarium Willing at Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
13 records from Herbarium BSG Vascular Plants
13 records from Findings of plants and fungi from &quot;Desna-Starohutskyi&quot; National Nature Park (Desna river basin)
13 records from South Dakota State University, C. A. Taylor Herbarium
13 records from Merseyside BioBank (unverified)
13 records from Marie-Victorin Herbarium (MT) - Plantes vasculaires
13 records from Plant collection Natuurmuseum Brabant, Tilburg
13 records from Herbier de Strasbourg
13 records from Weed species of the Central Urals (Sverdlovsk region)
14 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB, CSIC-Ajuntament de Barcelona), BC-Plantae
14 records from Vascular Plant Collection
14 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
14 records from Herbarium specimens of the Muséum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle of Aix-en-Provence (AIX)
14 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
14 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
14 records from Inventaire des pelouses calcicoles du PNR du Marais Poitevin 2017
15 records from University of Manitoba Herbarium (WIN) - Vascular Plant Collection
15 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (IBK) in China, Guangxi Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences
15 records from Black Hills State University Herbarium
15 records from Relevés of Main Vegetation Types of the Prioksko-Terrasnyi Biosphere Reserve (2019-2020)
15 records from Vascular Plants, Field notes, Oslo (O)
15 records from Flora of the Volga River basin
15 records from Digitization of plant specimens from Rhoen and Vogelsberg (FULD)
15 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
15 records from H.A. Stephens Herbarium
15 records from The Danish Environmental Portal, species and habitats-database &quot;Danmarks Miljøportals Naturdatabase&quot;
16 records from n_niek_2021
16 records from Flora of the Korean Peninsula Phase II
17 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (HIB) in China, Wuhan Botanical Garden, Chinese Academy of Sciences
18 records from Herbarium of Namur
18 records from Olga Lakela Herbarium, University of Minnesota Duluth
18 records from Données de la flore d’Alsace (SBA)
19 records from FloraCAT: Banco de datos de los cormófitos de Cataluña
19 records from Carnet B Lorraine
20 records from TULGU Herbarium: Tula Oblast collections of vascular plants
20 records from Suffolk Biodiversity Information Service (SBIS) Dataset
20 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB
21 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla
21 records from Natural History Museum Rotterdam - Specimens
21 records from A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in Udomlya District of Tver Oblast, Russia
21 records from DEMNA-DNE : Exotic plant occurrences in Wallonia
21 records from INRAE Villa Thuret
22 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL)
22 records from KULPOL Herbarium: Tula Oblast collections of vascular plants
22 records from A grid database on vascular plant distribution in the Meshchersky National Park, Ryazan Oblast, Russia
22 records from Kastikka Small Collections
22 records from Données acquises dans le cadre de l&apos;activité du bureau d&apos;étude BIOTOPE (1994 - 2013)
23 records from Vascular Plant Collection - University of Washington Herbarium (WTU)
23 records from Herbier du Québec (QUE) - Collection de plantes vasculaires
23 records from Relevés floristiques du protocole de l&apos;Inventaire National Forestier de l&apos;IGN
23 records from Atlas des plantes vasculaires de Lorraine
24 records from Scottish SNH-funded BSBI records
24 records from Charles University Prague - Herbarium PRC
24 records from A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in Samoylovsky District of Saratov Oblast, Russia
24 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
25 records from CeDoc de Biodiversitat Vegetal: BCN-Cormophyta
25 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
25 records from Plant Resources Center
26 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
26 records from Weed plants of the European part of Russia
27 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
27 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
27 records from A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in the Meshchera National Park, Vladimir Oblast, Russia
27 records from Royal BC Museum - Herbarium (V)
28 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares de la Universidad de Salamanca: SALA
28 records from Locations of plants on dot distribution maps in the Flora of Siberia (Flora Sibiraea, 1987–1997)
28 records from Wikiplantbase #Toscana
29 records from Vascular plant herbarium, UiT Tromsø Museum
29 records from Inventaire permanent de la flore du massif armoricain
29 records from Description of vegetation plots with Iris aphylla L. in European Russia
30 records from Flore de Franche-Comté
30 records from Natural History Museum Maastricht (NL) - Herbarium
32 records from Occurrences of vascular plants in the western part of Baikal-Amur Mainline
32 records from Carnet B Centre - lot 2012
32 records from Waarnemingen.be - Non-native plant occurrences in Flanders and the Brussels Capital Region, Belgium
33 records from Herbarium of Jyväskylä University Museum
33 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
35 records from Dataflos
35 records from Vascular plant specimens of National Museum of Nature and Science (TNS)
35 records from Biologiezentrum Linz
35 records from Herbarium of Taiwan Forestry Research Institute
35 records from Montana State University Billings
38 records from Carnet en Ligne
38 records from Occurrence Data of Vascular Plants from Abandoned Agricultural Fields (Moscow and Tula Regions, Russia)
38 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
39 records from INSDC Sequences
39 records from Royal Ontario Museum Green Plant Herbarium (TRT)
40 records from TUL Herbarium: Tula Oblast collections of vascular plants
40 records from Naturhistorisches Museum Mainz, Feldbeobachtungsdaten Pflanzen
42 records from Vascular Plants, Observations, Oslo (O)
44 records from Colorado State University Herbarium
44 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Herbarium
45 records from NIEK_NES
45 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
45 records from CONN
45 records from Other BSBI Scottish data up to 2015
46 records from Geneva Herbarium – De Candolle&apos;s Prodromus (G-DC)
48 records from Kathryn Kalmbach Herbarium
48 records from Wikiplantbase #Emilia-Romagna
49 records from Hatikka.fi observations
50 records from Herbier Louis-Marie (QFA) - Collection de plantes vasculaires
50 records from Vascular plant herbarium (KMN) UiA
50 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
51 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
52 records from Vascular plant herbarium TRH, NTNU University Museum
54 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum Görlitz (GLM)
54 records from Données ONF faune-flore-fonge
55 records from University of Alberta Vascular Plant Herbarium (ALTA-VP)
55 records from Species of plants, fungi and animals from separate territories of Podesinnia
56 records from IBF Monitoring of Vascular Plants
56 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
57 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
57 records from The Fungal Collection at the Senckenberg Museum für Naturkunde Görlitz
61 records from TUR Vascular plant collections of the Turku University, Herbarium generale
71 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, UiB
72 records from Pl@ntNet observations
73 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
73 records from KUZ Herbarium: collections of vascular plants
75 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Anthos. Sistema de Información de las Plantas de España
77 records from Collections and observation data National Museum of Natural History Luxembourg
77 records from Botany (UPS)
79 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
79 records from Some Plant Specimens from KUN, IBSC, NAS  Herbarium in China from 1900 to 1950
83 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
83 records from Biodiversitätsdatenbank Salzburg
85 records from flora &amp; fauna(NIBR)
85 records from EDP Foz-Tua: Macrophytes – Ecological Monitoring Program [2011-2015]
88 records from United Herbaria of the University and ETH Zurich
90 records from Atlas Flora Danica
97 records from Estonian Museum of Natural History Department of Botany
99 records from MHA Herbarium: collections of vascular plants
99 records from University of Tartu Natural History Museum and Botanical Garden Botanical Collections
99 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
101 records from Observations floristiques floutées issues de la base de données flore du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
109 records from Botanical Collections of the Åbo Akademi (TUR-A)
110 records from Norwegian Species Observation Service
120 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
124 records from University of Vienna, Institute for Botany - Herbarium WU
125 records from BSBI data from several English counties, up to 2015
130 records from Herbarium Universitatis Daugavpiliensis
135 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
139 records from Belgian IFBL Flora Checklists (1939-1971)
139 records from Steiermärkisches Landesmuseum Joanneum - Herbarium GJO
142 records from Some Plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1900 to 1950
144 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
151 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
153 records from Flore Franco-Belge
157 records from Kastikka Literature Sources
164 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
165 records from Oskarshamn herbarium (OHN)
168 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
168 records from Floristic Databases of Mecklenburg-Pomerania - Higher Plants
169 records from The MAGNOLIOPSIDA of Herbarium named after prof. B.M. Kozo-Polyansky VSU
172 records from Phytochorologie des départements français
175 records from TAXA - Flore et habitats naturels de Franche-Comté
178 records from Bell Museum plants
188 records from Floristic records from survey studies of the Bayerisches Landesamt für Umwelt
190 records from Données d&apos;occurrences Espèces issues de l&apos;inventaire des ZNIEFF
207 records from Plant
207 records from 500,000 plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1950 to 1999
218 records from Flora of Vladimir Oblast, Russia: an updated grid dataset (1867–2020)
222 records from Observations floristiques issues de la base de données du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
231 records from naturgucker
233 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium: Herbarium Generale
250 records from Local floras of Russia: a compilative dataset
258 records from Estonian Naturalists’ Society
258 records from Estonian University of Life Sciences Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Vascular Plant Herbarium
278 records from Université Lyon 1
302 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
332 records from Observations floristiques - plateforme SINP régionale SILENE   PACA
388 records from Swiss National Databank of Vascular Plants
400 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
406 records from EDP Foz-Tua: Vascular Flora and Habitats – Ecological and Complementary Measures Monitoring Programs – Construction Phase II [2015-2016] and Flooding Phase [2016-2017]
446 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
465 records from Waarnemingen.be - Plant occurrences in Flanders and the Brussels Capital Region, Belgium
530 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
535 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
555 records from Kastikka Floristic Archives (Kastikka Ark)
641 records from Records of vascular plants, bryophytes and lichens from Ukrainian Grassland Database
716 records from Florabank1 - A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in the northern part of Belgium (Flanders and the Brussels Capital region)
718 records from Masaryk University - Herbarium BRNU
796 records from EDP Foz-Tua: Vascular Flora – Ecological and Complentary Measures Monitoring Programs – Contruction Phase I [2012-2014]
1143 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
1172 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
1199 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
1454 records from Observations du Conservatoire botanique national du Bassin parisien.
1465 records from Artportalen (Swedish Species Observation System)
1542 records from FLORIVON
1832 records from Occurrence Data of Vascular Plants collected or compiled for the Flora of Bavaria
1836 records from Dutch Vegetation Database
2763 records from Flore du Bassin parisien (CBNBP)
2882 records from INPN - Données flore des CBN agrégées par la FCBN
3748 records from BLM - National Invasive Species Information Management System - Plants
6085 records from Observation.org, Nature data from around the World
9118 records from Flora von Deutschland (Phanerogamen)</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T03:48:53Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.varh2v">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.varh2v</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130656-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
