<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.f9pwmx"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130628-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.f9pwmx</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Centaurea solstitialis L.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Herbario EMMA. Herbario de la Escuela Técnica Superior de Ingenieros de Montes. UPM
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla, SEV-Historico
1 records from Herbarium of Jyväskylä University Museum
1 records from Plant Specimens of Kurashiki Museum of Natural History
1 records from ALA species sightings and OzAtlas
1 records from Flora exsiccata Bavarica
1 records from The Erysiphales Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
1 records from Universidad Politécnica de Madrid, Dpto. Biología Vegetal, Banco de Germoplasma
1 records from Museu Darder de Banyoles
1 records from Plant specimens depodited in Osaka Museum of Natural History, Japan
1 records from Clémence Lortet herbarium
1 records from Photographs of higher plants, mosses, fungi, lichens, and algae
1 records from FloVegSI - Floristical and fitocenological database of ZRC SAZU
1 records from Floristic records from survey studies of the Bayerisches Landesamt für Umwelt
1 records from Polish gene bank – passport data of plants accessions which are important in human life
1 records from Observations floristiques PNM issues de la base de données flore du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
1 records from Botany Division, Yale Peabody Museum
1 records from Dr Mary Gillham Archive Project
1 records from Botanical Collections of the Åbo Akademi (TUR-A)
1 records from UKSBA Cyprus - Habitat Samples, 2019
1 records from Rotherham Biological Records Centre - Non-sensitive Records from all taxonomic groups
1 records from Données naturalistes de Pierre HUGUENY
1 records from Muséum d&apos;histoire naturelle de Nîmes
1 records from HCDAL - Herbário Caririense Dárdano de Andrade-Lima
1 records from MHA Herbarium: collections of vascular plants
1 records from PAMP-tracheo: Vascular plants in Ribera Occidental de Navarra (Spain). PhD project, L. Garde
1 records from PlutoF platform reference-based occurrences
1 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
1 records from BODATSA: Botanical Collections
1 records from MPUC - Herbário do Museu da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
1 records from Observations faune et flore du Parc national des Écrins
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 44
1 records from Universidad de Navarra, Herbarium: PAMP-Vascular Plants
1 records from Royal Ontario Museum Green Plant Herbarium (TRT)
1 records from Inventaire permanent de la flore du massif armoricain
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Bordeaux Métropole 2013
1 records from Eastern Kentucky University, Ronald L. Jones Herbarium
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - United States (Contiguous) V2.0
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Herbiers Universitaires de Clermont-Ferrand (CLF)
1 records from Earth Guardians Weekly Feed
1 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
1 records from Conventions d’étude sur la biodiversité française – Partenariats du Service du patrimoine naturel
1 records from Living Collection of the Gothenburg Botanical Garden
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 57
1 records from IPA - Herbário - IPA Dárdano de Andrade Lima
1 records from Données naturalistes de GAULTIER Cyrille
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Limoges university (LIMO)
1 records from JCT AVH data
1 records from Plants of Ukrainian flora from collections of M. I. Berezhnyj
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 122
1 records from Clemson University Herbarium
1 records from Données naturalistes de Cyril EPICOCO
1 records from Magnoliophyta del Herbario BAB (Instituto de Recursos Biológicos CIRN-INTA)
1 records from SPF - Herbário da Universidade de São Paulo
1 records from ICN - Herbário do Instituto de Ciências Naturais
1 records from IICT Herbário LISC
1 records from University of Alberta Vascular Plant Herbarium (ALTA-VP)
1 records from NMNH Material Samples (USNM)
1 records from B herbarium - Botanischer Garten und Botanisches Museum Berlin-Dahlem Herbarium - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Tasmanian Natural Values Atlas
1 records from Muséum d’histoire naturelle de Grenoble
1 records from BioFokus
1 records from HUEFS - Herbario da Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana
1 records from Herbier Louis-Marie (QFA) - Collection de plantes vasculaires
1 records from CESJ - Herbário Leopoldo Krieger
1 records from Collection botanique Jaubert et Saul (BOUM)
1 records from HO AVH data
1 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
1 records from Données ONF faune-flore-fonge
1 records from SDSU - San Diego State University Herbarium
1 records from Some botanical researches of the Faculty of Biology of Taras Shevchenko national university of Kyiv (1930s-2000s)
1 records from Données espèces - Expertise IQE 2
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2015
1 records from Collection botanique Le Grand A. (BOUM)
1 records from ALCB - Herbário Alexandre Leal Costa
1 records from Sammlung altes Gartenherbar Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
1 records from SEWBReC Vascular Plants (South East Wales)
1 records from Application INPN Espèces: Observations naturalistes, participatives et opportunistes, fondées sur des photographies
1 records from Jeu de données convention FEGVE-SPN-2012-2016
1 records from Herbier Durrieu (TL 109)
1 records from Twelve local floras of European Russia
1 records from Vascular plant specimens of Akita Prefectural Museum
1 records from Collection botanique Mulon L. (BOUM)
1 records from IBF Monitoring of Vascular Plants
1 records from BRERC species records from all years at full resolution excluding Notable Species within the last 10 years
1 records from Carnet B Centre - lot 2012
2 records from Botanical Garden Collection
2 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
2 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
2 records from Herbário João de Carvalho e Vasconcellos, I.S.A./U.L.
2 records from Vascular plant specimens of National Museum of Nature and Science (TNS)
2 records from Israel Nature and Parks Authority
2 records from melu_avh
2 records from Plant specimens in the Museum of Nature and Human Activities, Hyogo Prefecture, Japan
2 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
2 records from Herbario de la Universidad Pública de Navarra, Pamplona: UPNA-H
2 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
2 records from Norwegian Species Observation Service
2 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
2 records from The Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Goettingen
2 records from Wikiplantbase #Emilia-Romagna
2 records from Type herbarium, Göttingen (GOET)
2 records from HAS - Herbário Alarich Rudolf Holger Schultz
2 records from Données naturalistes de Jeanne VALLET
2 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
2 records from Kastikka Literature Sources
2 records from Invasive Plant Atlas of the MidSouth (IPAMS)
2 records from Allan Herbarium (CHR)
2 records from Welsh BSBI data (ex-VPDB dataset) at hectad resolution
2 records from University of Graz, Institute of Plant Sciences - Herbarium GZU
2 records from Collection d&apos;animaux marins et plantes du Museum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle de Nice
2 records from Geneva Herbarium – Burnat Herbarium (G-BU)
2 records from CONN
2 records from H.A. Stephens Herbarium
2 records from Herbarium specimens of Association des Naturalistes de la Vallée du Loing (ANVL)
2 records from Colección preservada Jardín Botánico de la Patagonia Extraandina
2 records from Estonian University of Life Sciences Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences Vascular Plant Herbarium
2 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
2 records from FUEL - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Londrina
2 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Living Plant Collections (E)
3 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
3 records from Herbario COFC de la Universidad de Córdoba: colección histórica
3 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
3 records from TUR Vascular plant collections of the Turku University, Herbarium generale
3 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO-Briof
3 records from Données naturalistes de Damien AVRIL
3 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
3 records from University of New Mexico Herbarium
3 records from Herbier E. P. Larchevêque (BOUM)
3 records from Plant Resources Center
3 records from Vascular plant herbarium, UiT Tromsø Museum
3 records from Vascular plant herbarium TRH, NTNU University Museum
3 records from Floristic Databases of Mecklenburg-Pomerania - Higher Plants
3 records from Herbarium specimens of CBNA (GAP)
3 records from Central Siberian Botanical Garden Herbarium (NS, NSK)
3 records from Herbarium specimens of Jardins botaniques and Conservatoire Botanique of Nancy (NCY)
3 records from Chapter 7: Linnaean Plant Names and their Types (part C)
3 records from Weber State University Herbarium
3 records from New records in vascular plants alien to Kyrgyzstan
3 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
3 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Herbarium
3 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
3 records from Malezas introducidas en México
3 records from DNA AVH data
3 records from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium
3 records from Royal BC Museum - Herbarium (V)
3 records from Muséum des Volcans
3 records from Steiermärkisches Landesmuseum Joanneum - Herbarium GJO
3 records from Estonian Museum of Natural History Department of Botany
3 records from Kastikka Small Collections
3 records from Colección Plantas Vasculares - Herbario del Departamento de Biología, Bioquímica y Farmacia de la Universidad Nacional del Sur
3 records from Dutch Vegetation Database
3 records from Cartografía de vegetación a escala de detalle 1:10.000 de la masa forestal de Andalucía
3 records from Catálogo Florístico Histórico de Navarra. Gobierno de Navarra
4 records from Dataflos
4 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO
4 records from Jardín Botánico de Córdoba: Herbarium COA
4 records from Staatliches Museum für Naturkunde Stuttgart, Herbarium
4 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum Görlitz (GLM)
4 records from Oklahoma Vascular Plants Database Provider
4 records from Atlas Flora Danica
4 records from Vascular Plant Specimen database of Kanagawa Prefectural Museum of Natural History
4 records from MGC Herbarium of University of Malaga (Spain): MGC-Cormof dataset
4 records from SysTax - Herbaria
4 records from Données d&apos;occurrences Espèces issues de l&apos;inventaire des ZNIEFF
4 records from Charles University Prague - Herbarium PRC
4 records from Shropshire Ecological Data Network database
4 records from Muséum d’histoire naturelle du Mans
4 records from Manchester Museum, University of Manchester, Botany Collection
4 records from Natural History Museum Maastricht (NL) - Herbarium
4 records from University of Lethbridge Herbarium (LEA)
4 records from PERTH AVH data
5 records from Herbario ABH (Universidad de Alicante)
5 records from Herbario COFC de la Universidad de Córdoba: colección general de plantas vasculares
5 records from inatura - Erlebnis Naturschau Dornbirn
5 records from Colorado State University Herbarium
5 records from Herbarium specimens, Harmas J.H. Fabre (FABR - Sérignan-du-Comtat) of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
5 records from MCCC - Mendocino College Coast Center Herbarium
5 records from LERN Records
5 records from Michigan State University Herbarium Vascular Plants
5 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Ciencias Biológicas de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MACB)
5 records from Flore de Franche-Comté
5 records from University of Jena, Herbarium Haussknecht - Herbarium JE
5 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
5 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
5 records from UCSC Herbarium - Kenneth S. Norris Center for Natural History, University of California Santa Cruz
6 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
6 records from Kathryn Kalmbach Herbarium
6 records from Banco de Datos de la Biodiversidad de la Comunitat Valenciana
6 records from Precis Plant Data
6 records from Herbarium of University of Coimbra (COI )
6 records from INSDC Sequences
6 records from Wikiplantbase #Liguria
6 records from Puntos de presencia en Baja California (Botany)
6 records from UNSW AVH data
6 records from Rutgers University, Chrysler Herbarium
6 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
6 records from Staten Island Museum
6 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, UiB
7 records from Leiner-Herbar Konstanz
7 records from Jardin Botanique de Lyon
7 records from VIT Herbarium - Vascular Plants (The Natural History Museum of Alava)
7 records from Conservation Atlas Surveys
7 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
7 records from PRECIS
7 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
7 records from SFV - California State University, Northridge
7 records from OAC-BIO Herbarium
7 records from Université d&apos;Aix-Marseille
8 records from Herbario HSS Finca La Orden-Valdesequera (CICYTEX). Junta de Extremadura
8 records from Scottish SNH-funded BSBI records
8 records from Biodiversitätsdatenbank Salzburg
8 records from Données naturalistes de Thomas GAILLARD
8 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
8 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
9 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares de la Universidad de Salamanca: SALA
9 records from Base de datos de plantas vasculares del País Vasco: ARAN-EH
9 records from Botany (UPS)
9 records from Florient - a database dealing with historic wild plant occurrences
9 records from Florabank1 - A grid-based database on vascular plant distribution in the northern part of Belgium (Flanders and the Brussels Capital region)
9 records from FLORUS: miscellaneous records
9 records from Local floras of Russia: a compilative dataset
9 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario de la Universidad de Granada.
10 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
10 records from Herbarium specimens of the Muséum d&apos;Histoire Naturelle of Aix-en-Provence (AIX)
10 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
10 records from Suffolk Biodiversity Information Service (SBIS) Dataset
10 records from Levantamiento florístico en área del Proyecto GEF Corredores Biológicos de Montaña, Zona Central de Chile
11 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
11 records from Wikiplantbase #Sardegna
11 records from Herbarium Erlangense
11 records from University of Vienna, Institute for Botany - Herbarium WU
11 records from Vascular plant herbarium (KMN) UiA
11 records from Oskarshamn herbarium (OHN)
11 records from UCSB - University of California Santa Barbara Herbarium
11 records from Données acquises dans le cadre de l&apos;activité du bureau d&apos;étude BIOTOPE (1994 - 2013)
12 records from Herbarium of Namur
12 records from SFSU - Vascular Plants of the Harry D. Thiers Herbarium at San Francisco State University
12 records from Other BSBI Scottish data up to 2015
13 records from Données naturalistes d&apos;Olivier ESCUDER
13 records from Flora of Worcestershire
13 records from Wikiplantbase Sicilia
13 records from Artportalen (Swedish Species Observation System)
13 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
13 records from INRAE Villa Thuret
14 records from NE AVH data
14 records from Collections of Bioclass, school #179, Moscow
14 records from Records of vascular plants, bryophytes and lichens from Ukrainian Grassland Database
14 records from Herbarium Horti Botanici Pisani (PI), Sistema Museale di Ateneo, Università di Pisa
14 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
15 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
15 records from Tiroler Landesmuseum Ferdinandeum
16 records from Segetal flora of Italy
16 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
16 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB
16 records from Waarnemingen.be - Non-native plant occurrences in Flanders and the Brussels Capital Region, Belgium
18 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
19 records from Données Herbiers de l&apos;Université de Strasbourg
21 records from Colección de Asterales del Museo Botánico CORD
21 records from United Herbaria of the University and ETH Zurich
21 records from Geneva Herbarium – De Candolle&apos;s Prodromus (G-DC)
21 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
22 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
23 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
24 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL)
24 records from MEL AVH data
25 records from Vascular Plant Collection - University of Washington Herbarium (WTU)
25 records from Vascular Plant Collection
25 records from Collections and observation data National Museum of Natural History Luxembourg
26 records from Masaryk University - Herbarium BRNU
27 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
27 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla
27 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB, CSIC-Ajuntament de Barcelona), BC-Plantae
27 records from Victorian Biodiversity Atlas
27 records from Herbier de Strasbourg
28 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
29 records from CeDoc de Biodiversitat Vegetal: BCN-Cormophyta
29 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
29 records from HSC - Humboldt State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
30 records from Données de la flore d’Alsace (SBA)
31 records from Instituto de Botánica Darwinion
32 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
33 records from BRI AVH data
35 records from TAXA - Flore et habitats naturels de Franche-Comté
36 records from CANB AVH data
37 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
38 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
40 records from Australasian Virtual Herbarium (AVH) data from the State Herbarium of South Australia (AD)
42 records from Wikiplantbase #Italia
48 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
52 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
53 records from Herbarium Willing at Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
53 records from Palynology of a sediment profile from Lake Voulkaria in Greece
54 records from Observation.org, Nature data from around the World
60 records from NSW AVH data
61 records from naturgucker
62 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
64 records from Herbarium  BAK
65 records from Carnet en Ligne
67 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
68 records from SA Flora (BDBSA)
72 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
72 records from SBBG - Clifton Smith Herbarium, Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
76 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
76 records from Sistema de Información de la vegetación Ibérica y Macaronésica
79 records from Pl@ntNet observations
80 records from FLORIVON
83 records from Observations floristiques issues de la base de données du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
86 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
86 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium: Herbarium Generale
87 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
104 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
107 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
107 records from Observations floristiques floutées issues de la base de données flore du Conservatoire botanique national alpin
111 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Anthos. Sistema de Información de las Plantas de España
117 records from Wikiplantbase #Toscana
118 records from Swiss National Databank of Vascular Plants
119 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
123 records from Occurrence Data of Vascular Plants collected or compiled for the Flora of Bavaria
126 records from BSBI data from several English counties, up to 2015
145 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
149 records from Université Lyon 1
151 records from Phytochorologie des départements français
152 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
158 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
201 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
299 records from Observations du Conservatoire botanique national du Bassin parisien.
379 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
484 records from FloraCAT: Banco de datos de los cormófitos de Cataluña
516 records from Pl@ntNet automatically identified occurrences
633 records from Flore du Bassin parisien (CBNBP)
637 records from NSW BioNet Atlas
652 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
994 records from Flora von Deutschland (Phanerogamen)
1323 records from Observations floristiques - plateforme SINP régionale SILENE   PACA
1724 records from INPN - Données flore des CBN agrégées par la FCBN
2406 records from BLM - National Invasive Species Information Management System - Plants</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T03:41:18Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.f9pwmx">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.f9pwmx</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130628-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
