<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.6d9r8z"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0130733-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.6d9r8z</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-02-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [
    &quot;is Alternanthera philoxeroides (Mart.) Griseb.&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL)
1 records from CeDoc de Biodiversitat Vegetal: BCN-Cormophyta
1 records from Jardín Botánico de Córdoba: Herbarium COA
1 records from Herbario de la Facultad de Farmacia de la Universidad Complutense de Madrid (MAF)
1 records from Herbário João de Carvalho e Vasconcellos, I.S.A./U.L.
1 records from Herbarium of Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Extremadura (Spain)
1 records from Herbario HSS Finca La Orden-Valdesequera (CICYTEX). Junta de Extremadura
1 records from ALA species sightings and OzAtlas
1 records from Plants of Papua New Guinea
1 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
1 records from MAR - Herbário do Maranhão
1 records from Observation.org, Nature data from around the World
1 records from NE AVH data
1 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
1 records from MBML-Herbario - Herbário Mello Leitão
1 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
1 records from BOTU - Herbário Irina Delanova Gemtchújnicov
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad Pública de Navarra, Pamplona: UPNA-H
1 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
1 records from BRBA herbarium - Universidade Federal do Oeste da Bahia - Herbário Virtual Reflora
1 records from National vegetation diversity inventory and mapping plan
1 records from VIT Herbarium - Vascular Plants (The Natural History Museum of Alava)
1 records from Western Carolina University Herbarium
1 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
1 records from Registros biológicos  en áreas protegidas obtenidos de documentos impresos
1 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
1 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (LBG) in China, Lushan Botanical Garden, Jiangxi and Chinese Academy of Sciences
1 records from HST - Herbário Sérgio Tavares
1 records from Plantas vasculares del Herbario JBN del Jardín Botánico Nacional, Chile
1 records from ASE herbarium - Universidade Federal de Sergipe - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Colección del Herbario PSO de la Universidad de Nariño
1 records from ERBG AVH data
1 records from Sammmlung Ule Brasilien Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2015
1 records from EAC herbarium - Universidade Federal do Ceará - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
1 records from EAC - Herbário Prisco Bezerra
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
1 records from Herbario de la Universidad Industrial de Santander
1 records from HUESB - Herbário da Universidade Estadual do Sudoeste da Bahia
1 records from Royal Ontario Museum Green Plant Herbarium (TRT)
1 records from Global Register of Introduced and Invasive Species - United States (Contiguous) V2.0
1 records from VIES herbarium - Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Museo Argentino de Ciencias Naturales &quot;Bernardino Rivadavia&quot; (MACN). Actuopalynology National Collection (BAPa)
1 records from Herbarium specimens of Jardins botaniques and Conservatoire Botanique of Nancy (NCY)
1 records from Sistematización del Herbario Nacional Forestal Biól Luciano Vela Gálvez
1 records from OBI - Robert F. Hoover Herbarium, Cal Poly State University
1 records from S herbarium - Naturhistoriska Riksmuseet - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from SJRP - Herbário de São José do Rio Preto
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2016
1 records from Plant specimens of Takatsuki Nature Museum (Aquapia Akutagawa)
1 records from UFMT - Herbário UFMT
1 records from University of Graz, Institute of Plant Sciences - Herbarium GZU
1 records from Guadeloupe_Herbier
1 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
1 records from UFG - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Goiás
1 records from University of Cincinnati, Margaret H. Fulford Herbarium - Vascular Plants
1 records from IAC - Herbário do Instituto Agronômico de Campinas
1 records from MBML Herbarium - Museu de Biologia Mello Leitão - Herbário Virtual Reflora
1 records from Plantas Vasculares del Uruguay (Observaciones Mai &amp; Rossado)
1 records from CIRAD
1 records from Herbario Nacional Colombiano (COL)
1 records from WOLL AVH data
1 records from HUEM herbarium - Universidade Estadual de Maringá - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Depuración de la colección y base de datos del Herbario CICY. Fase IV
1 records from UPCB herbarium - Universidade Federal de Paraná - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Institut Menorquí d&apos;Estudis. Herbarium Generale Minoricae: HGM
1 records from MACF - MacFadden Herbarium, California State University Fullerton
1 records from Inventaire de la flore de Gironde 2014
1 records from Herbarium - Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas da Amazônia (INPA)
1 records from Oskarshamn herbarium (OHN)
1 records from LA - University of California, Los Angeles Herbarium
1 records from HUSC - Herbário Unisanta
1 records from UAM Herbarium (ALA), Vascular Plant Collection (Arctos)
1 records from Vascular Plant Specimens of Yamagata Prefectural Museum
1 records from Plantas Vasculares del Uruguay (Observaciones González)
1 records from Botanical Research Intitute of Texas
1 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
1 records from UNOP Herbarium - Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Paraná - Herbário Virtual Reflora
2 records from Herbarium Specimens of Museum of Nature and Human Activities, Hyogo Pref., Japan
2 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB, CSIC-Ajuntament de Barcelona), BC-Plantae
2 records from CVRD - Herbário da Reserva Natural Vale
2 records from Plantas Vasculares del Uruguay (Observaciones Fagúndez-Pachón)
2 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
2 records from Colección de plantas vasculares de Brasil del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB-Brasil
2 records from Colección de Herbario LP
2 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
2 records from MO herbarium -  Missouri Botanical Garden - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from JPB - Herbário Lauro Pires Xavier
2 records from SLUI - Herbário Rosa Mochel
2 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
2 records from HPL - Herbário do Jardim Botânico Plantarum
2 records from Earth Guardians Weekly Feed
2 records from ECT herbarium - Embrapa Clima Temperado - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from South Dakota State University, C. A. Taylor Herbarium
2 records from CRI Herbarium - Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense - Herbário Virtual Reflora
2 records from BHZB - Herbário do Jardim Botânico da Fundação Zoo-Botânica de Belo Horizonte
2 records from Bioimages
2 records from Marie-Victorin Herbarium (MT) - Plantes vasculaires
2 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
2 records from Database of Vascular Plants of Himalaya
2 records from Buffalo Society of Natural Sciences Clinton Herbarium
2 records from PRECIS
2 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
2 records from Herbarium Specimens of The Kagoshima University Museum (KAG)
2 records from NMNH Material Samples (USNM)
2 records from Phytochorologie des départements français
2 records from SMDB - Santa Maria Departamento de Biologia
2 records from HBRA - Herbário do Instituto de Estudos Costeiros da Universidade Federal do Pará
2 records from Université Lyon 1
2 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2014
2 records from HO AVH data
2 records from Rapid Assessment Program (RAP) Biodiversity Survey Database
2 records from Museo Argentino de Ciencias Naturales &quot;Bernardino Rivadavia&quot; (MACN). Vascular Plants National Collection (BAv)
2 records from ASE - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Sergipe
2 records from Appalachian State University, I. W. Carpenter, Jr. Herbarium
3 records from Oklahoma Vascular Plants Database Provider
3 records from Australasian Virtual Herbarium (AVH) data from the State Herbarium of South Australia (AD)
3 records from Alien Flora of Nepal at KATH
3 records from Database of Native Plants in Taiwan
3 records from HVAT - Herbário do Vale do Taquari
3 records from Weeds in Australia
3 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
3 records from Carnet en Ligne
3 records from CRI - Herbário Pe. Dr. Raulino Reitz
3 records from Wikiplantbase #Italia
3 records from JOI Herbarium - Univille\Universidade da Região de Joinville - Herbário Virtual Reflora
3 records from UB - Herbário da Universidade de Brasília
3 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
3 records from SysTax - Herbaria
3 records from MOSS - Herbário Dárdano de Andrade Lima
3 records from UESC - Herbário Universidade Estadual de Santa Cruz
3 records from JOI - Herbário Joinvillea
3 records from Rutgers University, Chrysler Herbarium
3 records from DNA AVH data
3 records from CONN
3 records from Inventaire de la flore de Lot-et-Garonne 2015
3 records from Colección Botánica-Herbario. Museo de Ciencias Naturales y Antropológicas “Juan Cornelio Moyano” (Mendoza, Argentina)
3 records from CESJ herbarium - Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora UFJF - Herbário Virtual Reflora
3 records from naturgucker
3 records from COR herbarium - Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul / Campus Pantanal - Herbário Virtual Reflora
3 records from EAFM - Herbário do Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia do Amazonas
3 records from University of Colorado Museum of Natural History Herbarium Vascular Plant Collection
4 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
4 records from Vascular Plants Collection of Sagamihara City Museum
4 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
4 records from MAC - Herbário do Instituto do Meio Ambiente do Estado de Alagoas
4 records from MAC herbarium - Instituto do Meio Ambiente do Estado de Alagoas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
4 records from Berea College, Ralph L. Thompson Herbarium
4 records from LOB - California State University, Long Beach Herbarium
4 records from Museu Paraense Emilio Goeldi Herbarium
4 records from CESJ - Herbário Leopoldo Krieger
4 records from PERTH AVH data
4 records from FUEL - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Londrina
4 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
5 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
5 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
5 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (IBK) in China, Guangxi Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences
5 records from Endemic Species Research Institute–Herbarium
5 records from India Biodiversity Portal publication grade dataset
5 records from BHCB - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais
5 records from Arkansas Natural Heritage Commission Herbarium
5 records from WIKTROP - Weed Identification and Knowledge in the Tropical and Mediterranean areas
5 records from OUPR - Herbário &quot;Professor José Badini&quot;
5 records from PMSP herbarium - Prefeitura do Município de São Paulo - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
5 records from FCAB - Herbário Friburguense
5 records from HPBR - Herbário Padre Balduino Rambo
5 records from Weeds Australia
6 records from Vascular Plant Specimen database of Kanagawa Prefectural Museum of Natural History
6 records from PEUFR - Herbário Professor Vasconcelos Sobrinho
6 records from RBR herbarium - Universidade Federal Rural do Rio de Janeiro - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
6 records from H.A. Stephens Herbarium
6 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
6 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
7 records from Vascular Plant Collection of Natural History Museum and Institute, Chiba
7 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
7 records from FLOR herbarium - Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
7 records from CEPEC - Herbário do Centro de Pesquisas do Cacau
7 records from Eastern Kentucky University, Ronald L. Jones Herbarium
7 records from Some Plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1900 to 1950
7 records from FLOR - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica da Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina
7 records from EFC - Herbário Escola de Florestas Curitiba
7 records from Pl@ntNet observations
7 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
8 records from Ibaraki Nature Museum, Vascular Plants collection
8 records from Pittsburg State University, Theodore M. Sperry Herbarium
8 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
8 records from IRAI - Herbário do Parque da Ciência Newton Freire Maia
8 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
9 records from ESA - Herbário da Escola Superior de Agricultura Luiz de Queiroz
9 records from ESA herbarium - Universidade de São Paulo - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
9 records from CGMS herbarium - Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
9 records from HUEM - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Maringá
9 records from Plant Specimen from Herbarium (CDBI) in China, Chengdu Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences
9 records from Nomenclatura, tipificaciones y sinónimos nuevos en la familia Amaranthaceae de la Flora del Paraguay
9 records from VIC - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Viçosa
10 records from George Mason University, Ted R. Bradley Herbarium
10 records from HRCB - Herbário Rioclarense
10 records from Dataset from Herbarium of Endemic Species Research Institute, Taiwan (TAIE) 2021
11 records from Great Eastern Ranges - Southern Highlands
11 records from UEC - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Campinas
12 records from IPA - Herbário - IPA Dárdano de Andrade Lima
12 records from SPF herbarium - Universidade de são Paulo - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
12 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
13 records from Canberra Nature Map
13 records from UFP - Herbário UFP - Geraldo Mariz
13 records from VIES - Herbário Central da Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo
13 records from ALCB - Herbário Alexandre Leal Costa
14 records from IAN herbarium - Embrapa Amazônia Oriental - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
14 records from CGMS - Herbário da Fundação Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul
14 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
14 records from SPF - Herbário da Universidade de São Paulo
16 records from FURB herbarium - Universidade Regional de Blumenau - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
16 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium: Herbarium Generale
16 records from MBM herbarium - Museu Botânico Municipal \ Curitiba - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
17 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
18 records from NY herbarium - The New York Botanical Garden - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
18 records from CDA - California Department of Food and Agriculture
18 records from FURB - Herbário Dr. Roberto Miguel Klein
18 records from CPAP - Herbário CPAP
18 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
18 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
19 records from Fairchild Tropical Botanic Garden (FTG)
20 records from BRI AVH data
21 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
21 records from Colección de  Bruniales, Buxales, Canellales y Caryophyllales del Museo Botánico CORD - IMBIV
21 records from K herbarium - Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
21 records from US herbarium - Smithsonian Institute - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
21 records from HUEFS herbarium - Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
22 records from alien_flora_of_nepal_tuch
23 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
23 records from Some Plant Specimens from KUN, IBSC, NAS  Herbarium in China from 1900 to 1950
23 records from HUEFS - Herbario da Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana
23 records from MEL AVH data
25 records from Macrophyte Lake Data
25 records from MPUC - Herbário do Museu da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
25 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
25 records from Wikiplantbase #Toscana
26 records from HURB - Herbário do Recôncavo da Bahia
26 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
28 records from HAS - Herbário Alarich Rudolf Holger Schultz
29 records from Herbário da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná - HUCP
29 records from HUCP herbarium - Pontífica Universidade Católica do Paraná PUC - Herbário Virtual Reflora
30 records from The digitization of plant specimens of NTU
32 records from MISS_DC_01MAR2006
32 records from UPCB - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica
34 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
36 records from Allan Herbarium (CHR)
39 records from Plant Resources Center
39 records from ICN - Herbário do Instituto de Ciências Naturais
41 records from INPN - Données flore des CBN agrégées par la FCBN
42 records from 500,000 plant Specimens from PE Herbarium in China from 1950 to 1999
43 records from Herbarium (UNA)
44 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
46 records from PACA-AGP - Herbarium Anchieta
48 records from Clemson University Herbarium
49 records from University of Florida Herbarium (FLAS)
49 records from CANB AVH data
54 records from INSDC Sequences
55 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
55 records from Instituto de Botánica Darwinion
56 records from Pl@ntNet automatically identified occurrences
59 records from University of Tennessee Vascular Herbarium
63 records from Freshwater Pest Plants
67 records from P herbarium - Muséum national d’histoire naturelle, Paris - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
76 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
77 records from Freshwater Pest Plants Observations
78 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
78 records from NSW AVH data
85 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
85 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
87 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
90 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
100 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
100 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
122 records from Observations floristiques - plateforme SINP régionale SILENE   PACA
129 records from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium
136 records from LSU Shirley C. Tucker Herbarium at Louisiana State University - Vascular Plants
205 records from Herbarium of Taiwan Forestry Research Institute
233 records from Alien plant presence dataset from the point-radius plot surveys in 2010-2015 in Taiwan
301 records from NSW BioNet Atlas
365 records from Invasive Plant Atlas of the MidSouth (IPAMS)
998 records from Victorian Biodiversity Atlas
18810 records from USGS Nonindigenous Aquatic Species database</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-02-08T04:13:00Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.6d9r8z">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.6d9r8z</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0130733-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
